export const courseData1 = {
        // Level 100, Semester 1, Chemical Engineering
"Technical Drawing":{
programOfStudy: 'Chemical Engineering',
levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
Easy: [
    {
        question: 'In Technical drawing, a numerical linear dimension specified without a unit signifies',
        answer: 'Millimeters (mm)',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['foot (ft)','Inches (in)','Centimeters (cm)','Millimeters (mm)']
    },
    {
        question: 'A wooden pencil sharpened conically should be rotated between the fingers while drawing a straight line, because:',
        answer: 'It ensures a constant line thickness',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['It is elegant','It ensures a sharp and clear line','It ensures a constant line thickness','It ensures a neat drawing']
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following letters on a wooden pencil will signify the hardest lead?',
        answer: '3H',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['HB','3H','2H','H']
    },
    {
        question: 'The ratio of thin lines to thick lines recommended for standard drawing  is: ',
        answer: '1:2',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['1:1','1:2','1:3','2:1']
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following drawing tool cannot qualify as a template?',
        answer: '60/30 and 45 Set-squares',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Sets of Circle','60/30 and 45 Set-squares','Sets of Ellipse','French curves']
    },
    {
        question: 'All title blocks must contain at least one of the following information EXCEPT',
        answer: 'Dimensions',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Title of drawing','Name and dates of the drafter, checker and designer','Dimensions','Scale']
    },
    {
        question: 'The ratio of the size of drawing of a part or machine to its actual size irrespective of the unit of measurement used is called a/an',
        answer: 'Scale',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Sketch','Scale','Drawn size','Actual size']
    },
    {
        question: 'A circle is a plane figure bounded by the circumference that is always equidistant from a fixed point known as ..............',
        answer: 'quadrant',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['chord','radius','segment','centre','quadrant']
    },
    {
        question: 'Which type of line has precedence over all type of lines?',
        answer: 'Continuous Thick Line',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Continuous Thick Line','Centre Line','Continuous Thin Line','Hidden Line','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'A/An ..............is created by the motion of a point on a circle as the circle rolled along a straight line',
        answer: 'cycloid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['cycloid','epicycloid','hypocycloid','spiral','none of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'If a length of 1m on land is represented by 2cm on a drawing, what is the ratio of the scale used?',
        answer: '1:50',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['1:20','1:200','1:40','1:400','1:50']
    },
    {
        question: 'How many pairs of parallel lines are there in a regular Hexagon',
        answer: '3',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['1','2','3','6','None of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'The tools required for geometric construction include',
        answer: 'Pair of compasses',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Drawing board','T-square','Pair of compasses','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'All the following are plane figures except',
        answer: 'Cones',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Polygons','Cones','Circles','Triangles']
    },
    {
        question: 'The intersection of the perpendicular bisectors of two chords give a/an...............',
        answer: 'Centre',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Circle','Arc','Centre','Radius']
    },
    {
        question: 'A line is said to be................to another line if it touches the line but does not cross it.',
        answer: 'Tangential',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Concentric','Parallel','Perpendicular','Tangential']
    },
    {
        question: 'The distance between the centres of two circles is R+r. What is the relatonship between the two circles?',
        answer: 'External tangency',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['External intersection','Internal intersection','External tangency','Internal tangency']
    },
    {
        question: 'The distance between the centres of two circles is R-r. What is the relatonship between the two circles?',
        answer: 'Internal tangency',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['External intersection','Internal intersection','External tangency','Internal tangency']
    },
    {
        question: 'For an external tangential relationship between two circles, which of the following statements is true:',
        answer: 'The point of tangency and the centres of the two circles must lie on a straight line',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['The point of tangency and the centres of the two circles lie on a semi-circle','The point of tangency and the centres of the two circles form a right angle','The point of tangency and the centres of the two circles must lie on a straight line','The point of tangency and the centres of the two circles lie on a circle']
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following curves is not a conic section',
        answer: 'Epicycloid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Ellipse','Parabola','Hyperbola','Epicycloid']
    },
    {
        question: 'An accurate ellipse was required. Which of the following methods should be applied',
        answer: 'Concentric circle method',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Four centre method','Rhombus method','Concentric circle method','None of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'The semi-circle (Right-triangle) theorem is applied in Principles of Tangency to construct a tangent to an arc or circle through a point',
        answer: 'Outside the cicle/arc',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['On the circle/arc','Within the circle/arc','Outside the cicle/arc','None']
    },
    {
        question: 'The semi-circle (Right-triangle) theorem is a principle that can be apllied to construct ............',
        answer: 'All of the above',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['A common exterior tangent to two unequal circles','A common interior tangent to two unequal circles','A tangent to an arc through a point outside the arc','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the distance between the centres of two circles (R=50, r=20) that are externally tangential.',
        answer: '70',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['30','35','50','70']
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the distance between the centres of two circles (R=70, r=20) that intesect one another. ',
        answer: 'None of the above',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['30','40','50','None of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'The following are types of plane curves except',
        answer: 'All of the above',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Cycloidal curves','Involutes','Spirals','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'A/An.................is generated by a point on the circumference of a circle that rolls along a fix straight line.',
        answer: 'Cycloid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Epicycloid','Trochoid','Cycloid','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'A/An.................is generated by a point on the circumference of a rolling circle which rolls outside a directing circle',
        answer: 'Epicycloid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Epicycloid','Trochoid','Cycloid','All of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'A/An.................is generated by a point within or outside the circle that rolls along a staright line',
        answer: 'Trochoid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Cycloid','Trochoid','Involute','Spiral']
    },
    {
        question: 'A/An.................is a curve traced out by a point on a piece of string when unwound from any geometrical object.',
        answer: 'Involute',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Hypocycloid','Involute','Circle','Trochoid']
    },
    {
        question: 'The curve generated by a point moving continuously in one direction along a rotating line is called...............',
        answer: 'Spiral',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Involute','Spiral','Cycloid','Trochoid']
    },
    {
        question: '..................is generated by a point within or outside a circle which rolls on the inside of the directing circle',
        answer: 'Hypotrochoid',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Hypotrochoid','Hypocycloid','Epitrochoid','Trochoid']
    },
    {
        question: 'Selection of views in Orthographic Projection are guided by the following rules. Which rule is considered first?',
        answer: 'The rule of stability',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['The rule of the longest side','The rule of stability','The rule of the most natural position','The rule of minimum dash lines or hidden details']
    },
    {
        question: 'In the first angle orthographic projection, the object is imagined to be placed',
        answer: 'Above the HP and in front of the VP',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Below the HP and behind the VP','Above the HP and in front of the VP','Above the HP and behind the VP','None of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'Of all the types of projections, orthographic projection has been of prior importance in describing objects to the engineer. Which of the following characteristics makes orthograhic projection exceptional to the engineer?',
        answer: 'It has self-correcting mechanisms',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['It is drawn to scale','It is drawn to the same shape','It can be dimensioned ','It has self-correcting mechanisms']
    },
    {
        question: 'The first most important view of an object is during Orthographic Projection is captured on:',
        answer: 'Vertical plane',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['Vertical auxillary plane','Horizontal plane','Vertical plane','Auxillary plane']
    },
    {
        question: 'The following are properties of Othographic projection EXCEPT',
        answer: 'It is a single-view projection',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['The rays are orthogonal to the planes of projection','Only one side or surface is exposed to the rays','The rays are parallel to one another','It is a single-view projection']
    },
    {
        question: 'In a reduction scale drawing, the drawing is of:',
        answer: 'Reduced size of the object',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['The same size as the object','Reduced size of the object','Bigger size as the object','Only some area that is reduced']
    },
    {
        question: 'The student is required to purchase clutch (mechanical) pencils for producing engineering drawings. Which combination sizes of pencils will suit this purpose?',
        answer: '0.7 and 0.35',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        options: ['0.7 and 0.35','0.7 and 0.5','0.5 and 0.35','0.7 and 0.3']
    },
    {
        question: 'A T-square in conjunction with a set square is required for horizontal lines.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'The Path traced by a point attached within a circle that rolls on the outside of another circle is called inferior hypotrochoid.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'The Path traced by a point on a circle that rolls on a straight line is called inferior cycloid.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'Epitrochoids, Involutes of polygons, Spirals and Helices are plane curves',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'On the basis of Distance between Object and Ray, projections can be termed as perspective and parallel ray projection',
        answer: 'True',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'Hidden outlines are indicated in drawings with thick continuous lines.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'Only line type A (thick continuous) and line type D (thin short dashes) represent edges.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'The lengths and spacing of the elements of thick chain lines should differ from those of thin chain lines.',
        answer: 'True',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'When thin chain lines are used as centre lines, they should cross one another at solid portions of the line.',
        answer: 'True',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'When an invisible line continues a visible line, the invisible line start with a dash',
        answer: 'True',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'All chain lines, E, should start and finish with a short dash.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
        options: ['True','False',]
    },
],
Medium: [
    {
        question: 'When visible line and invisible line coincide in a drawing, the visible line takes precedence.',
        answer: 'True',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'When invisible line and centre line coincide in a drawing, the centre line takes precedence.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'Dashed lines should meet at corners and tangent points with dashes.',
        answer: 'False',
        type: 'True/False',
    },
    {
        question: 'The instrument used for joining points to obtain both small and large arcs is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice ',
        answer: 'French curves',
        options: ['Fillet plate','Circles plate','French curves','Radius plate']
    },
    {
        question: 'A reflex angle is an angle',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Greater than 180 but less than 360',
        options: ['Greater than 90 but less than 180','less than 90','exactly equal to 90','Greater than 180 but less than 360']
    },
    {
        question: 'A quadrilateral that has all the sides equal and the opposite angles equal is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Rhombus',
        options: ['Kite','Rectangle','Rhombus','Trapezium']
    },
    {
        question: 'The line drawn form the center of a circle to any point on the circumference is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Radius',
        options: ['Arc','Diameter','Raadius','Chard']
    },
    {
        question: 'The circumference of a circle is its',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Perimeter',
        options: ['Area','Perimeter','Arc','Diameter']
    },
    {
        question: 'The sum of the angles of a right angled triangle is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '180',
        options: ['60','90','150','180']
    },
    {
        question: 'A regular tetrahedron is a',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'triangular pyramid',
        options: ['triangular pyramid','Rectangular pyramid','Pentagonal prism','Hexagonal prism']
    },
    {
        question: 'The front view of a right cone is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Triangular',
        options: ['Rectangular','Square','Triangular ','Circular']
    },
    {
        question: 'A plane figure with more than four straight sides is a',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Polygon',
        options: ['Quadrilateral','Parallelogram','Tramezium','polygon']
    },
    {
        question: 'In archimedean spiral the curve made in one  revolution is refered to as',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Convoluton',
        options: ['Convolution','Resorvation','Cycloid','Helix']
    },
    {
        question: 'Similar figures are those that have the same shape but',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Different in areas',
        options: ['Different in sizes','No regular shape is required','Different in areas','No dimension is required']
    },
    {
        question: 'The dimension of A3 drawing sheet is ',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '420 mm x 297 mm',
        options: ['841 mm x 591 mm','594 mm x 420 mm','420 mm x 297 mm','291 mm x 210 mm']
    },
    {
        question: 'The length 1.0 meter on land is represented by 4.0 cm on a drawing, the scale used is  ',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '1:25',
        options: ['1:20','1:25','1:40','1:50']
    },
    {
        question: 'The locus which uses two concentric circles as a method for its construction is a/an',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'ellipse',
        options: ['Cycloid','Hyperbola','Parabola','ellipse']
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following views is not on a principal plane',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Auxiliary',
        options: ['Front elevation','Auxiliary','Plan','End elevation']
    },
    {
        question: 'Isometic views are drawn to the horizontal with which of the following pairs of angles',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '30 and 60',
        options: ['30 and 60','45 and 60','30 and 90','45 and 90']
    },
    {
        question: 'The eccentricity of a parabola is',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '1',
        options: ['1/2','3/4','1','3/2']
    },
    {
        question: 'The locus of a point on the circumference of cicle when the cicle rolls without slipping along the inside of a bigger arc is ',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Hypo-cycloid',
        options: ['Hypo-cycloid','Parabola','Epi-cycloid','Trochoid']
    },
    {
        question: 'The foci of an ellipse are obtained by using one end of the ',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: 'Minor axis as centre and half the minor axis to describe an arc to intercept the major axis',
        options: ['Minor axis as centre and half the major axis as radius to describe an arc to intercept the major axis','Major axis as centre and half the minor axis to describe an arc to intercept the major axis','Minor axis as centre and half the minor axis to describe an arc to intercept the major axis','Minor axis as centre and the lenght of the minor axis to describe an arc to intercept the major axis']
    },
    {
        question: 'The scale of a drawing is the ratio....',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['The same size as the object','Reduced size of the object','bigger size as the object','Only some area that is reduced','None of the above']
    },
    {
        question: 'The image length of the edge of an object is 10 mm. What is the true length of the object given that the scale of the drawing is 1:5',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['2 mm','10 mm','25 mm','50 mm','50 cm']
    },
    {
        question: 'The first most important view of an object during orthographic projection is captured on',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['Vertical auxiliary plane','Horizontal plane','Auxiliary plane','Horizontal auxiliary plane'] 
    },
    {
        question: 'In third angle projection, the object is imagined to be placed',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['below the HP and behind the VP','below the HP and in front the VP','above the HP and in front of the VP','above the HP and behind the VP']
    },
    {
        question: 'The surface of an object appears in its true shape when it is............. to the plane of the projection',
        type: 'Fill-in',
        answer: '',
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the difference between the Superior and Inferior Trochoid.................',
        type: 'Fill-in',
        answer: '',
    },
    {
        question: 'To draw a horizontal line, the appropriate drawing tool is .........',
        type: 'Fill-in',
        answer: '',
    },
    {
        question: 'Given the 2H, 2B, 3H, 3B, HB lead type pencils, arrange them in order of hardness with the softer one first.........',
        type: 'Fill-in',
        answer: '',
    },
    {
        question: 'The following are properties of orthographic projection except',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['the rays are othogonal to the planes of projections','only one side or surface face is expose to the rays','the rays are parallel to one another','it is a single-view projection','it is a multiple-view projection']
    },
    {
        question: 'A student is requested to purchase clutch (mechanical) pencils for producing engineering drawing. which combination pencil size will suit this purpose?',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['0.7 and 0.35','0.7 and 0.5','0.5 and 0.35','0.7 and 0.3','1.0 and 0.7']
    },
    {
        question: 'Hidden edges and outlines can be represented by',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['Thin continuous lines','Thin chain lines','Thin short dashes','Thick continuous lines','Thick chain lines']
    },
    {
        question: 'The following information cannot be found in the title block',
        type: 'Multiple Choice',
        answer: '',
        options: ['Size of object','Title of drawing','scale','names and date of drafter, checker, designer','Name of firm']
    },
]},
'Algebra' : {
    programOfStudy: "Chemical Engineering",
    levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
    semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
    Easy: [
        {
            question: "The set of natural numbers is not closed under multiplication.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The sum of any two irrational numbers is always irrational.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The principle of mathematical induction is used to prove statements for all natural numbers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",   
        },
        {
            question: "If a∙b=0, then a and b must be parallel vectors.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",   
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of a complex number  is given by |z|=√(a^2+b^2 )",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True", 
        },
        {
            question: " The equation x^2+1=0 has no real solution.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: " Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n complex roots.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "The rational number 2/3 is a subset of the set of integers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False", 
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always zero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "If two vectors are orthogonal, their dot product is nonzero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: " Which of the following is an irrational number?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "√2",
            options: ['5/2','3.14','√2','1.5']
        },
        {
            question: "Which property states that a(b+c)=ab+ac ?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Distributive Property",
            options: ['Associative Property','Commutative Property','Distributive Property','Closure Property']
        },
        {
            question: "What is the complex conjugate of 4+3i?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "4-3i",
            options: ['4-3i','-4-3i','4+3i','4,3i']
        },
        {
            question: "The argument of the complex number -3+4i lies in which quadrant?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Second",
            options: ['First','Second','Third','Fourth']
        },
        {
            question: "If a and b are two nonzero vectors, their dot product is given by:",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "|a||b|cos∅",
            options: ['|a||b|sin∅','|a||b|cos∅','|a||b|tan∅','|a|+|b|']
        },
        {
            question: " What is the solution to the equation x^2=-9 in the set of complex numbers?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "±3i",
            options: ['No solution','±3','±3i','±√9']
        },
        {
            question: "If |z|=5 and z=3+bi, what is b?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Both a and b",
            options: ['4','-4','Both a and b','None']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is a unit vector?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "1/√2 i+1/√2 j",
            options: ['3i+4j','5i-2j','i+j','1/√2 i+1/√2 j']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Force",
            options: ['Speed','Temperature','Force','Mass']
        },
       
        {
            question: "The additive inverse of  is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "-7",  
        },
        {
            question: "The square root of -1 is represented by the symbol _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "i",   
        },
        {
            question: "The set of real numbers consists of both rational and _______ numbers.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "irrational", 
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of the complex number 6-8i is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "10",
        },
        {
            question: "The dot product of two perpendicular vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "A vector with a magnitude of 1 is called a _______ vector.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "unit",
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the sum of  3+4i and 2-5i.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "5-i",
        },
        {
            question: " Find the argument of -1+i.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "arctan(-1)+180",
            options: ['arctan(-1)+180','arcsin(-1)+180','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
        {
            question: " Solve for x in 2x+3=7.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the roots of x^2-4x+4=0.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "If z=e^(-i×π/3),express z in rectangular form.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "5/2+(5√3)i/2",
            options: ['5/2+(5√3)i/2','5/2-(√3)i/2','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
    ]},
    "Inorganic Chemistry":{
        programOfStudy: "Chemical Engineering",
        levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
        semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
        Easy : [
            {
                question: "When an electron drops from a higher energy level to a low energy level then",
                answer: "energy is emitted",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['energy is emitted','energy is absorbed','atomic number increase','atomic number decrease']
            },
            {
                question: "Of the following the one that is not an elementary particle is",
                answer: "particle",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['proton','neutron','particle','electron']
            },
            {
                question: "A helium molecule of 30k is moving with a velocity of 2.4 x 102ms-1. The de-Broglie wave length is about ",
                answer: "0.83 nm ",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['0.416 nm','0.83 nm','803 A','800 A']
            },
            {
                question: "The energy equivalent of the rest mass of an electron (9.1×10-31 kg)",
                answer: "8.1x 10-14 J",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['8.1 J','27.3 x 10^-10J','8.1x 10^-11 J','8.1x 10^-14 J']
            },
            {
                question: "Using arbitrary energy units, it is calculated that 80 arbitrary units (a.u) are needed to transfer electron in a hydrogen atom from the most stable Bohr orbit to a large distance from the nucleus",
                answer: "40a.u",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['5a.u','10a.u','20a.u','40a.u']
            },
            {
                question: "Isotonic are atoms having the same",
                answer: "number of neutrons",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['atomic mass','mass number','atomic number','number of neutrons']
            },
            {
                question: "The particle discovered in the anode ray experiments is the",
                answer: "Proton ",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Neutron','Proton','Electron','Meson']
            },
            {
                question: "The number of protons present in the atom of an element is known as the",
                answer: "Atomic Weight ",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Atomic Weight','Proton Number','Proton Number','Atomic Number']
            },
            {
                question: "The smallest particle of an element which can take part in chemical reactions and may or may not exist independently is the",
                answer: "Atom",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Nucleus','Atom','Neutron','compound']
            },
            {
                question: "The sum of the numbers of the protons and neutrons in the atom of an element is known as",
                answer: "Mass Number",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Mass Number','Isotope Number','Molecular Weight','Atomic Number']
            },
            {
                question: "The charge on the electron was discovered by",
                answer: "Mullikan",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['J. J. Thomson','Mullikan','Fermi','Faraday']
            },
            {
                question: "The Atomic Theory was given by",
                answer: "John Dalton",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['J. J. Thomson','E. Rutherford','James Chadwick','John Dalton']
            },
            {
                question: "According to Rutherford, ",
                answer: "Electrons revolve around the nucleus",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Protons revolves around the nucleus','Nucleus revolves around the electrons','Neutrons revolve around the nucleus','Electrons revolve around the nucleus']
            },
            {
                question: "The alpha particle scattering experiment was carried out by",
                answer: "E. Rutherford",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['J. J. Thomson','E. Goldstein','J. Chadwick','E. Rutherford']
            },
            {
                question: "As a result of Rutherford's scattering experiment, it was concluded that ",
                answer: "atomic mass is spread over the whole atom",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['the center of the atom is empty','most of the atom is empty','the center of the atom has a negative charge','atomic mass is spread over the whole atom']
            },
            {
                question: "The particle discovered as a result of cathode ray experiments is the",
                answer: "electron",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['nucleus','proton','neutron','electron']
            },
            {
                question: "The three fundamental particles of the atom are",
                answer: "Proton, Neutron and Electron",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Mesons, Quarks and Anti-neutrino','Positron, Neutrino and Gamma Rays','Nucleus, Anti-quarks and Electrons','Proton, Neutron and Electron']
            },
            {
                question: "The charge by mass ratio for electrons of various elements",
                answer: "is the same",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['increases with increase in atomic mass','decreases with increase in atomic mass','increases with increase in atomic number','is the same']
            },
            {
                question: "The charge on the electron was discovered by",
                answer: "Mullikan",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Faraday','Fermi','Mullikan','J. J Thomson']
            },
            {
                question: "According to Rutherford, the atom consists of the following two parts",
                answer: "Nucleus and the extra-nuclear part",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Electrons and Protons','Protons and Neutrons','Neutrons and Electrons','Nucleus and the extra-nuclear part']
            },
            {
                question: "The currently accepted model of the atom is that of",
                answer: "Heisenberg",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Bohr','de Broglie','Rutherford','Heisenberg']
            },
            {
                question: "Neutron was discovered by",
                answer: "James Chadwick",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['E. Goldstein','John Dalton','E. Rutherford','James Chadwick']
            },
            {
                question: "Huygens Wave Theory could not explain, ____ ",
                answer: "All these",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['All these','Polarization','Compton Effect','Photoelectric Effect']
            },
            {
                question: "The Drawbacks of Newton’s Corpuscular Theory is that it cannot explain",
                answer: "All of above",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Interference','Diffraction','Polarization','All of above']
            },
            {
                question: "According to Max Planck’s Quantum Theory, radiation is not continuous, but discontinuous packets of light called _______ ",
                answer: "Photons",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Photons','Energy','Neutrons','Electromagnetic radiation']
            },
            {
                question: "A wave is called periodic if:  ",
                answer: "disturbance is repeated in equal time intervals",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['disturbance is repeated in equal time intervals','disturbance is repeated in very long time intervals','disturbance is repeated in short time intervals']
            },
            {
                question: "The wavelength is defined as:  ",
                answer: "the distance traveled by a progressive wave in a period",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['the distance traveled by a progressive wave in a second','the distance traveled by a progressive wave in a minute','the distance traveled by a progressive wave in a period','the distance traveled by a progressive wave in a half period']
            },
            {
                question: "The frequency of a wave is expressed as: ",
                answer: "Hertz",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['second','Hertz','meter','lambda']
            },
            {
                question: "The electromagnetic wave is due to the spread of: ",
                answer: "An electromagnetic field",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['an electrical disturbance in a material medium','a magnetic disturbance in a material medium','an electromagnetic field','a magnetic field']
            },
            {
                question: "The speed of propagation of an electromagnetic wave in vacuum is:  ",
                answer: "3 x 10^8 m/s",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['3 x 10^6 m/s','0.3 x 10^7 m/s','3 x 10^8 m/s ','3 x 10^8 km/s']
            },
            {
                question: "If the frequency of an electromagnetic wave in vacuum is 600 kHz, its wavelength is equal to:  ",
                answer: "500 m",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['500 m','500 km','2000 m','5 km']
            },
            {
                question: "Calculate the energy (J) change associated with an electron transition from n = 2 to n = 5 in a Bohr hydrogen atom.",
                answer: "5.5 x 10^-19",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['6.5 × 10^-19','5.5 × 10^-19','8.7 × 10^-20','4.6 × 10^-19']
            },
            {
                question: "The frequency of electromagnetic radiation required to promote anelectron from n = 2 to n = 4 in a Bohr hydrogen atom is __________ Hz.",
                answer: "6.17 x 10^14",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['4.13 × 10^-19','6.17 × 10^14','5.46 × 10^-19','8.22 × 10^14']
            },
            {
                question: "A spectrum containing only specific wavelengths is called a __________ spectrum.",
                answer: "Line",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Line','Continuous','Visible','Rydberg']
            },
            {
                question: "The n = 2 to n = 6 transition in the Bohr hydrogen atom corresponds to the __________ of a photon with a wavelength of __________ nm.",
                answer: "Absorption, 410 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Emission, 410 nm','Absorption, 410 nm','Absorption, 660 nm','Emission, 94 nm']
            },
            {
                question: "The n = 5 to n = 3 transition in the Bohr hydrogen atom corresponds to the __________ of a photon with a wavelength of __________ nm.",
                answer: "Emission, 657 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Absorption, 657 nm','Absorption, 1280 nm','Emission, 657 nm','Emission, 1280 nm']
            },
            {
                question: "The potential energy of interaction between two static charges is: ",
                answer: "Inversely proportional to the distance separating the two charges",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Proportional to the distance separating the two charges','Inversely proportional to the distance separating the two charges','Inversely proportional to the square of the distance separating the two','Proportional to the square of the distance separating the two']
            },
            {
                question: "The expression of the momentum of a photon is :  ",
                answer: "p = h/λ",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['p = hλ','p = h/λ','p = c/λ','p = cλ']
            },
            {
                question: "The energy of a photon, expressed in eV, the visible light of wavelength",
                answer: "1.95 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1.95 eV','19.5 eV','0.195 eV','195 eV']
            },
            {
                question: "The wavelength, expressed in nm, of a photon of energy equal to 1 keV is equal to:    ",
                answer: "0.124 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['0.124 nm','1.24 nm','12.407 nm','124 nm']
            },
            {
                question: "The n = 8 to n = 4 transition in the Bohr hydrogen atom occurs in the _________ region of the electromagnetic spectrum.",
                answer: "Infrared",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Infrared','Visible','Ultraviolet','Microwave']
            },
            {
                question: "The n = 8 to n = 2 transition in the Bohr hydrogen atom occurs in the __________ region of the electromagnetic spectrum.  ",
                answer: "ultraviolet",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['radio','X-ray','infrared','microwave','ultraviolet']
            },
            {
                question: "At what speed (m/s) must a 3.0-mg object be moving in order to have a de Broglie wavelength ",
                answer: "2.0 x 10^12",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1.6 × 10^-28','3.9 × 10^-4','2.0 × 10^12','4.1 × 10^12']
            },
            {
                question: " The wavelength associated with an electron of energy E = 100 eV is equal to :  ",
                answer: "1.23 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1.23 nm','12.3 nm','123 nm','123 m']
            },
            {
                question: "The wavelength associated with a 2 g ball with a velocity of 100 m/s is equal to: ",
                answer: "2.38 x 10^-24 m",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['3.31 x 10^-33 m','3.31 x 10^-30 m','2.38 x 10^-24 m','2.38 x 10^-27 m']
            },
            {
                question: "According to the theory of Bohr, the energy values of the electron in a hydrogen atom is given by:  ",
                answer: "En = -13.58 / n^2 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['En = -13.58 / n eV','En = -13.58 / n^2 eV','En = 13.58 / n^2 eV','n being a positive integer : n = 1,2,3,…..∞']
            },
            {
                question: " The energy of photon emitted by one atom Bohr making a transition state with quantum number n = 5 to the state of quantum number n = 4 is equal to: ",
                answer: "0.68 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['0.55 eV','0.68 eV','0.30 eV']
            },
            {
                question: "  A Bohr atom initially in its ground state makes a transition to its first excited state after absorbing a photon. What is the wavelength of the photon absorbed?   ",
                answer: "122 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['55 nm','122 nm','181nm']
            },
            {
                question: " The largest wavelength of the Balmer series is equal to: ",
                answer: "365 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['365 nm ',' 434 nm','175nm']
            } ,
            {
                question: "The energy of an electron in the first orbit of hydrogen is 13.6eV. Which one of the following is the second excited state of electron in hydrogen atom?  ",
                answer: "-3.4 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['-3.4eV',' -6.8eV ','-1.5Ev ',' +3.4eV']
            }],
        Medium: [
            {
                question: "The energy of an electron in the first orbit of hydrogen is 13.6eV. Which one of the following is the second excited state of electron in hydrogen atom?  ",
                answer: "-3.4 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['-3.4eV',' -6.8eV ','-1.5Ev ',' +3.4eV']
            },
            {
                question: " The wave number of the first line in the Balmer series of hydrogen is 15200cm-1.The wavenumber of the first line in the Balmer series of Be3+ would be ",
                answer: "60800 cm^-1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['60800cm^-1',' 2.432 x 10^5 ',' 2.432 x 10^5 ','950cm^-1 ']
            },
            {
                question: "The wavenumber of the radiation emitted when the electron jumps from fourth energy level to second energy level in He+ is about",
                answer: " 41030 cm^-1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['20565 cm-1 ','41030 cm-1 ','82258 cm-1 ','5141 cm-1 ']
            },
            {
                question: " The wave number of an electromagnetic radiation is 1x105 cm-1. The frequency of the radiation would be ",
                answer: " 3 x 10^15 s^-1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 3x108s-1 ',' 3x106s-1 ',' 3x1010s-1','3x1015s-1 ']
            },
            {
                question: "  When an electronic transition occurs in an atom from higher energy state to  lower energy state with energy difference equal to ∆E electron volts, the wavelength of the radiation emitted is approximately equal to   ",
                answer: " 12397 x 10^-10 m /∆E",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 12397x10-10m/∆E',' 12397x10-10A/∆E ','12397x10-10cm/∆E',' 12397x1010cm/∆E']
            },
            {
                question: "What are the speed and momentum of a 500-nm photon? ",
                answer: " 2.998 x 10^8 m/s, 133 x 10^-27 kg·m/s",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['2.998 x 10^8 m/s, 133 x 10^-30 kg·m/s ','2.998 x 10^8 m/s, 133 x 10^-27 kg·m/s ','2.998 x 10^8 m/s, 7.52 x 10^6 kg·m/s','2.998 x 10^8 m/s, 133 x 10^-36 kg·m/s ']
            },
            {
                question: "Compute the de Broglie wavelength of an electron that has been accelerated through a potential difference of 9.0 kV. Ignore relativists effects. ",
                answer: "1.3 x 10^-11 m",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1.3 x 10-11 m ','1.7 x 10-22 m',' 1.2 x 10-26 m ','5.2 x 10-21 m ']
            },
            {
                question: " The wave-particle duality theory is the first to give an adequate explanation of which of the following facts about the hydrogen atom? ",
                answer: " Why only certain energies are possible for the orbiting electron",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Why more than one possible orbit exists for the electron.','Why only certain energies are possible for the orbiting electron.','Why more than one momentum is possible for the orbiting electron.','None of these are correct ']
            },
            {
                question: " The concept of dual nature of radiation was introduced by,  ",
                answer: "De Broglie",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Einstein ','Max Planck ','De Broglie ',' H.G.J. Mosley']
            },
            {
                question: " Rutherford’s experiment of a-particles showed for the firs time that atom has",
                answer: "Nucleus",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' Protons','Neutrons ','Nucleus ','Electrons ']
            },
            {
                question: " Which of the following transitions will emit maximum energy in the hydrogen atom?",
                answer: "All have same energy",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['4f-2s ','4d-2p','4p-2s','All have same energy ']
            },
            {
                question: "  The wavelength of a spectral line for electron transition in an atom is inversely proportional to ",
                answer: " The difference of energy between energy levels involved in the transition",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['velocity of electron ','number of electrons undergoing transition ','the difference of energy between energy levels involved in the transition ','the difference of energy between energy levels involved in the transition ']
            },
            {
                question: " The de Broglie equation suggests that an electron has",
                answer: "Particle as well as wave character",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['particle character','wave character','particle as well as wave character ',' none of the above statements is true']
            },
            {
                question: "The value of Bohr’s radius of hydrogen atom is ",
                answer: "0.529 x 10^-10 m",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 0.529 x 10-6cm','0.529 x 10-6m ','0.529 x 10-10cm',' 0.529 x 10-10m ']
            },
            {
                question: " Copper consists of 69.1% Cu-63 and 30.9% Cu-65. Calculate the relative atomic mass, Ar, of copper to 3sf/1dp.  ",
                answer: "63.6",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 6 ',' 64.0 ',' 63.6 ',' 63.3 ']
            },
            {
                question: " Bromine consists of the isotopes: 50.5% Br-79 and 49.5% Br-81. Calculate the relative atomic mass, Ar, of bromine to 3sf/1dp. ",
                answer: "80.1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 80.0 ','80.1 ','79.9','79.8']
            },
            {
                question: "Iron has four stable isotopes. 5.8% Fe-54, 91.7% Fe-56, 2.2% Fe-57 and 0.3% Fe-58. Calculate the Ar of iron to 3sf/1dp.  ",
                answer: "55.9",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['55.9','56.1','56.2','56.3']
  
            },
            {
                question: " Antimony (Sb) is 57.2% Sb-121 and 42.8% Sb-123. Calculate the Ar of Sb to 4sf/1dp.",
                answer: "121.9",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['121.2','121.9','122.1','122.0']
            },
            {
                question: "Boron is 19.7% B-10 and 80.3% B-11. Calculate the relative atomic mass, Ar, of boron to 3sf/1dp.",
                answer: "10.8",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['10.3','10.9','10.5','10.8']
            },
            {
                question: "The atomic mass of titanium is 47.88 atomic mass units. This atomic mass represents",
                answer: " Weighted average mass of all naturally occurring isotopes of Ti",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' weighted average mass of the most abundant isotope of Ti ',' total mass of all the protons, neutrons, and electrons in an atom of Ti ',' total mass of all the protons and neutrons in an atom of Ti ',' weighted average mass of all the naturally occurring isotopes of Ti ']
            },
            {
                question: "The average isotopic mass of chlorine is 35.5. Which mixture of isotopes (shown as percents) produces this average mass?",
                answer: "75% Cl-35 and 25% Cl-37",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 75% Cl-35 and 25% Cl-37','50% C-12 and 50% C-13',' 50% Cl-35 and 50% Cl-37 ','75% C-12 and 25% C-13 ']
            },
            {
                question: ". Calculate the wavelength of the lowest energy transition in the Brackett series of the electronic spectrum of the Li+ ion. The Rydberg constant for He is RLi = 109729 cm-1.",
                answer: "4050 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 450 nm ','4050nm ',' 91.1 nm ',' 30.3 nm']
            },
            {
                question: " A line in the Paschen series of the emission spectrum of atomic hydrogen is observed at a wavenumber of 7800 cm-1. Deduce the upper state principal quantum number for this transition.",
                answer: "7",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['7','6','4','2']
            },
            {
                question: " Calculate, from the fundamental constants, the value of the Rydberg constant for a deuterium atom.",
                answer: "109707 cm^-1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['109677 cm-1','109707 cm-1 ','109722 cm-1','109729 cm-1 ']
            },
            {
                question: ".What is the longest wavelength in the Lyman Series? ",
                answer: " 121.5 nm",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['45.60 nm. ',' 91.20 nm.  ',' 121.5 nm','240.1 nm. ']
            },
            {
                question: " To which of the following values of n does the longest wavelength in the Balmer series correspond?",
                answer: " ∞ ",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1','3','5','7','∞']
            },
            {
                question: " What energy photon emitted is when an electron in a hydrogen atom goes from the n= 5 energy level to the n= 2 energy level? ",
                answer: " 6.80 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['10.20 eV  ',' 13.60 eV',' 6.80 eV ',' 2.86 eV ']
            },
            {
                question: ". Calculate the de Broglie wavelength of a 0.145 kg baseball moving at a speed of 45.2 m/s (≈101 mph).  ",
                answer: "1.01 x 10^-34 m",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['1.01 × 10−34 m ',' 2.62 × 10−24 m','3.17 × 10−9 m','4.58 × 10−2 m ']
            },
            {
                question: " In the spectrum of hydrogen atom, the series which falls in ultraviolet region is ",
                answer: " Lyman series",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['Lyman series ',' Balmer series  ',' Paschen series ',' Brackett series']
            },
            {
                question: " The Balmer series in the spectrum of hydrogen atom falls in ",
                answer: " Visible region",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['ultraviolet region  ',' visible region  ',' infrared region  ',' none of these ']
            },
            {
                question: " Lyman series is obtained when the electrons from higher energy levels return to",
                answer: "1st orbit",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 1st orbit','2nd orbit ','3rd orbit ',' 4th orbit ']
            },
            {
                question: " A line in Pfund series is obtained when an electron from higher energy levels returns to ",
                answer: "5th orbit",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' 1st orbit  ','3rd orbit  ','5th orbit  ',' 6th orbit  ']
            },
            {
                question: " The energy of an electron in Bohr’s atom _______ as we move away from the nucleus ",
                answer: " Increases",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' remains the same ','decreases',' increases ','sometimes increases, sometimes decreases ']
            },
            {
                question: "  When an electron drops from a higher energy level to a lower energy level, then    ",
                answer: " Energy is released",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' the energy is absorbed  ','the energy is released  ','the nuclear charge increases','the nuclear charge decreases ']
            },
            {
                question: "The energy of an electron in the first Bohr orbit for hydrogen is ",
                answer: "-13.6 eV",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['13.6 eV  ',' –13.6 eV ',' 1.36 eV',' –1.36 eV ']
            },
            {
                question: " The spectral line lies in the Lyman series. It corresponds to the radiation emitted by an electron jumping from higher energy sates to    ",
                answer: "First energy state",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' first energy state ',' second energy state  ','third energy state  ',' fifth energy state']
            },
            {
                question: "  The ground state of an atom corresponds to a state of    ",
                answer: "Minimum energy",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['maximum energy  ','minimum energy ','zero energy ','negative energy ']
            },
            {
                question: " Balmer series in the spectrum of hydrogen atom lies in    ",
                answer: " Visible region",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' ultraviolet region  ',' visible region  ','infrared region  ','none of these ']
            },
            {
                question: " The spectrum of hydrogen atom is similar to that of  ",
                answer: "He+ ion",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['H+ ion  ',' He+ ion',' Li+ ion  ',' Na+ ion ']
            },
            {
                question: "  If r is the radius of first orbit, the radius of nth orbit of hydrogen atom will be ",
                answer: "n^2 r",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [ 'n^2 r' ,'n r',' n/r  ',' r/n ']
            },
            {
                question: "  The ratio of radii of second and first orbit of hydrogen atom according to Bohr’s model is   ",
                answer: "4:1",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: ['2:1',' 1:2','4:1 ',' 1:4 ']
            },
            {
                question: " . In Bohr’s model of atom, the angular momentum of an electron orbiting around the nucleus is given by the relation   ",
                answer: "mvr=nh/2π",
                type: "Multiple Choice",
                options: [' mvr=h/2π  ','mvr=nh/2π','mvr=n^2h^2/4π','mvr=nh/4π']
            },
            {
            question: "  The radius of first orbit in hydrogen atom according to Bohr’s Model is given by the relation   ",
            answer: "r=h^2/4π^2 me^2",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: ['r=h^2/4π^2 me^2','r=h^2/4π^2 m e^4','r=h^2/4π^2 m e','r=h^2/4π^2 m e^3']
            },
            {
            question: "  The radius of first orbit in hydrogen atom is 0.529 Å. The radius of second orbit is given by   ",
            answer: "2 × 0.529 Å  ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: ['½ × 0.529 Å  ','2 × 0.529 Å  ',' 4 × 0.529 Å  ',' 8 × 0.529 Å  ']
            },
            {
            question: "  The energy of an electron in the first orbit in hydrogen atom is –313.6/n2 kcal mol–1. The energy of the electron in 3rd orbit is given by the relation   ",
            answer: "E3 = 313.6 1 kcal mol-1/9 ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: ['E3 = 313.6 1 kcal mol-1/3','E3 = 313.6 1 kcal mol-1/2 ','E3 = 313.6 1 kcal mol-1/9 ','E3 = 313.6 3 kcal mol-1']
            },
            {
            question: " Of the following, __________ radiation has the shortest wavelength.  ",
            answer: " X-ray ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: ['  X-ray ','radio  ','microwave ',' ultraviolet ']
            },
            {
            question: "  Which one of the following is considered to be ionizing radiation?  ",
            answer: " X-ray ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: [' X-ray ',' radio ','microwave ','ultraviolet ']
            },
            {
            question: "  Of the following transitions in the Bohr hydrogen atom, the __________ transition results in the emission of the highest-energy photon.  ",
            answer: " n = 6 → n = 1",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: [' n = 1 → n = 6 ','n = 6 → n = 1 ','n = 6 → n = 3 ','n = 3 → n = 6 ']
            },
            {
            question: "  Of the following transitions in the Bohr hydrogen atom, the __________ transition results in the emission of the lowest-energy photon.  ",
            answer: " n = 6 → n = 3 ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: [' n = 1 → n = 6 ','n = 6 → n = 1 ','n = 6 → n = 3 ',' n = 3 → n = 6 ']
            },
            {
            question: "  In the Bohr model of the atom, __________.  ",
            answer: "electron energies are quantized ",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            options: [' electrons travel in circular paths called orbitals ',' electrons can have any energy ',' electron energies are quantized ','electron paths are controlled by probability ']
            },

        ]},
    'Organic Chemistry for Engineers': {
      programOfStudy: 'Chemical Engineering',
      levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
      semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
      Easy: [
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	characteristic	of	organic	compounds?",
        answer: "Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	usually	have	low	melting	points','They	usually	are	only	slightly	soluble	or	insoluble	in	water','If	water	soluble	they	seldom	conduct	an	electric	current.','Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	element	least	likely	to	be	found	in	an	organic	compound	is ......",
        answer: "silicon",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['oxygen','sulfur','nitrogen','silicon']
        },
        { 
        question: "One	of	the	major	sources	of	organic	compounds	is .....",
        answer: "Natural gas",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Natural gas','Fermentation', 'Sea water', 'Atmosphere']
        },
        { 
        question: "Catenation	is	a	property	of	the	carbon	atom	which	describes	its	ability	to ......",
        answer: "bond	with	other	carbon	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bond	with	other	carbon	atoms','form	double	and	triple	bonds', '	exist	in	plant	and	animal	form', 'form	bonds	in	its	ground	state']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	stable	organic	compounds,	carbon	will	always	form ....",
        answer: "4 bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	bonds','4	bonds','3	bonds','5 bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Carbon-carbon	double	bonds	consist	of?",
        answer: "one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond','two σ	bonds,	one	π	bond','one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','two	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Acetylene	has	a	total	of	:",
        answer: "three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','	two	σ	bonds,	four	π	bonds', 'three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds', 'one	σ	bond,	four	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	propene	there	are",
        answer: "eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond','seven	σ	bonds	and	two	π	bonds','six	σ	bonds	and	three	π	bonds','nine	σ	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "1-Buten-3-yne	has",
        answer: "seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['six	σ	and	four	π	bonds','seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds','eight	σ	and	two	π	bonds','nine	σ	and	one	π	bond']
        },
        { 
        question: "Compound	in	which	carbons	use	only	sp3	hybrid	orbitals	for	bond	formation is",
        answer: "CH3CH2CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','CH3C≡CH', 'CH3CH=CH2', 'CH2=CH—CH=CH2']
        },
        { 
        question: "When	the	carbon	atom	is	sp2	hybridized	in	a	compound,	it	is	bonded	to",
        answer: "3	other	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	other	atoms','4	other	atoms', '	3	other	atoms', '5	other	atoms']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	planar	molecule?",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Formaldehyde','Acetone', '	Formic	acid', 'Acetic	acid']
        },
        { 
        question: "	What	is	bond	angle	between	the	hybrid	orbitals	in	methane?",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['180°','	120°', '109.5°', '	115.5°']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–C	bond	angle	in	ethane	is",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','109.5°','120°','118°28']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–H	bond	angle	in	ethylene	is",
        answer: "120°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','120°', '90°', '180°']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	bond	length	of	a	carbon-carbon	double	bond?",
        answer: "1.34	Å",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	1.20	Å','1.34	Å', '	1.54	Å', '1.68	Å']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	lengths	in	rank	of	increasing	bond	length	is	:",
        answer: "triple,	double,	single",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['triple,	double,	single','single,	double,	triple', 'single,	double,	triple', 'triple,	single,	double']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	is	the	correct	order	of	bond	lengths	:",
        answer: "	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C','C–C	>	C≡C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	>	C–C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	<	C–C	>	C=C']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	hydrocarbons	has	the	shortest	C–C	bond	length?",
        answer: "HC≡CH",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','CH3CH3', 'HC≡CH']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	length	is	maximum	in",
        answer: "	CH3CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','	CH3CH3', '	HC≡CH', '']
        },
        { 
        question: "How	many	atoms	are	attached	to	an	atom	having	a	sp	hybridization?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['0','1', '2', '3']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	statement	is	true?",
        answer: "Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Resonance	hybrids	are	inherently	unstable','Resonance	hybrids	are	more	stable	than	any	individual	resonance	form', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	more stable	forms']
        },
        { 
        question: "	....... has same	arrangement	of	atom",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Ethyl	alcohol','Formaldehyde','Diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Resonance	structures	of	a	molecule	have",
        answer: "same	arrangement	of	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['same	arrangement	of	atoms','different	arrangement	of	atoms','different	number	of	paired	electrons','same	number	of	paired	electrons']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	have	planar	molecules?",
        answer: "formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ethyl	alcohol','formaldehyde', 'diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	show	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "cis-1,2-dichloroethylene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['cis-1,2-dichloroethylene','o-dichlorobenzene','trans-1,2-dichloroethylene','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	molecule	has	a	nonzero	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Cl2','CCl4', 'CHCl3','CH4']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons','The	greater	the	number	of	relatively	stable	resonance	contributors,	the	greater is	the	resonance	stabilization.', '	Delocalized	electrons	destabilize	a	compound.']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	correct?",
        answer: "Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	poor	center	to	an	electron rich	center.','A	doubled	headed	arrow	means	one	electron	has	been	moved.','Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.', 'A	single	headed	arrow	means	two	electrons	have	been	moved.']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	does	a	“curved”	arrow	represent?",
        answer: "the	movement	of	two	electron",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['that	two	structures	are	resonance	structures','the	movement	of	two	electron', 'a	link	between	reactants	and	products', 'that	two	structures	are	equivalent']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	predicted	shape,	bond	angle,	and	hybridization	for	CH3+?",
        answer: "trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2','trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp3', '	trigonal	planar,	109.5°,	sp2', '	trigonal	pyramidal,	120°,	sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	name	given	for	a	species	that	contains	a	positively	charged carbon	atom?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	carbanion','carbocation', '	methyl	radical', '	free	radical']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	orbitals	overlap	to	create	the	H–C	bond	in	CH3+",
        answer: "	s–sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	sp3–sp3','sp2–sp3', 's–p', '	s–sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	lone-pair	electrons	of	the	methyl	anion	occupy	a	__________	orbital.",
        answer: "sp3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['s','	sp', 'sp2', 'sp3']
        },
        { 
        question: "An	increase	in	which	of	the	following	results	in	a	decrease	in	the	rate	of	the chemical	reaction?",
        answer: "energy	of	activation",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['temperature','concentration', '	collision	frequency', 'energy	of	activation']
        },
        {
        question: "The	reaction	step	that	has	its	transition	state	at	the	highest	point	on	the reaction	coordinate	is	the	called	the	__________",
        answer: "rate-determining	step",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rate-determining	step','activation	energy','transition	step','	product	favored	step']
        },
        {
        question: "An	electrophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	a	nucleophile",
        answer: "Lewis	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	base','Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','	Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "A	nucleophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	an	electrophile",
        answer: "Lewis	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','	Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','Lewis	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	normally	considered	to	be	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "CH3CH2+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['NH3','CH3NH2','HC≡C:','CH3CH2+']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "FeBr3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['FeBr3','	Br','	NH3','	CH3OCH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	the	strongest	interaction?",
        answer: "	a	covalent	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	a	covalent	bond','dipole-dipole	interactions','	hydrogen	bonding','van	der	Waals']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Electrons	move	toward	positively	charged	locations.','	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.','	An	electrophile	is	electron	loving.','	A	nucleophile	has	a	a	pair	of	electrons	it	can	share.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	nonpolar	molecule?",
        answer: "H2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	HCl','CH3Cl','H2','NH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	is	defined	as	a	species	that	accepts	a	proton?",
        answer: "Bronsted-Lowry	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Lewis	acid','Lewis	base','	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct?",
        answer: "The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	base,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	acid.']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	conjugate	acid	of	CH3NH2?",
        answer: "CH3NH3+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3NH3+','CH3NH','	NH4+','NH2-']
        },
        {
        question: "A	molecule	is	said	to	be	chiral",
        answer: "	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	if	it	contains	plane	of	symmetry','if	it	contains	centre	of	symmetry','	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image','if	it	can	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	false	regarding	chiral	compounds?",
        answer: "have	cis	and	trans	isomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','have	cis	and	trans	isomers','	exist	as	enantiomers','	can	be	detected	with	a	polarimeter']
        },
        {
        question: "An	optically	active	compound",
        answer: "when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	must	contain	atleast	four	carbons','when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','	must	always	contain	an	asymmetric	carbon	atom','	in	solution	always	give	a	negative	reading	in	polarimeter.']
        },
        {
        question: "Plane-polarized	light	is	affected	by",
        answer: "Chiral	molecules",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['dentical	molecules','All	polymers','Chiral	molecules','All	biomolecules']
        },
        {
        question: "It	is	possible	to	distinguish	between	optical	isomers",
        answer: "by	polarimetry",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['by	using	chemical	tests','by	mass	spectrometry','by	IR	spectroscopy','by	polarimetry']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	mirror	images	are	called	:",
        answer: "Enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Tautomers','Diastereomers','Enantiomers','	Metamers']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	not	mirror	images	are	called",
        answer: "Diastereomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Diastereomers','	Enantiomers','Metamers','	Meso	compounds']
        },
        {
        question: "Enantiomers	have	which	of	the	following	characteristics?",
        answer: "have	the	same	melting	point",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	ordinary	light','have	the	same	melting	point','are	superimposable	mirror	images','react	with	optically	active	molecules	at	the	same	rate']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	false	about	enantiomers?",
        answer: "are	superimposable	mirror	images",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	plane-polarized	light','are	superimposable	mirror	images','are	nonsuperimposable	mirror	images','have	the	same	melting	point']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	possible	number	of	optical	isomers	for	a	compound	containing 2	dissimilar	asymmetric	carbon	atoms?",
        answer: "4",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "Meso-Tartaric	acid	is",
        answer: "always	optically	inactive",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sometimes	optically	active','always	optically	active','sometimes	optically	inactive','always	optically	inactive']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "2-Chloropropanoic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Propanoic	acid','	3-Chloropropanoic	acid','2-Chloropropanoic	acid','3-Chloropropene']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "	Lactic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Succinic	acid','	meso-Tartaric	acid','	Lactic	acid','Chloroacetic	acid']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct	concerning	a	pair	of enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and in	opposite	directions','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and	in	the	same direction','	They	have	different	melting	points']
        },
        {
        question: "A	and	B	are	stereoisomers.	They	are	nonsuperimposable	and	are	mirror images	of	one	another.	Which	of	the	following	best	describes	the	relationship between	A	and	B",
        answer: "enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['structural	isomers','enantiomers','cis-trans	isomers','diastereomers']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	true	of	enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	have	the	same	melting	point.','	They	have	the	same	boiling	point.','	They	have	the	same	density.','They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	correct	about	diastereomers?",
        answer: "	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.','	They	are	a	pair	of	identical	isomers.','They	are	a	pair	of	isomers	that	are	mirror	images.','All	their	asymmetric	centers	are	the	same.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is/are	optically	inactive?",
        answer: "all	the	above",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['50-50	mixture	of	R	and	S	enantiomers','a	meso	compound','a	racemic	mixture','all	the	above']
        },
        {
        question: "Hydrocarbons	are",
        answer: "both	(a)	and	(b)",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['insoluble	in	water','composed	of	carbon	and	hydrogen','both	(a)	and	(b)','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	hexane?",
        answer: "5",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['4','5','6','7']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	heptane",
        answer: "9",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['9','10','11','12']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	reactions	can	be	used	to	prepare	alkanes?",
        answer: "	Corey-House	synthesis",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Corey-House	synthesis','Williamson	synthesis','Friedel-Crafts	reactions','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "What	product	is	formed	in	the	free-radical	bromination	of	methane?",
        answer: "all	of	these",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bromomethane','dibromomethane','	tribromomethane','all	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "Chlorination	of	an	alkane	as	compared	to	bromination	proceeds",
        answer: "at	a	faster	rate",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['at	a	slower	rate','with	equal	rates','at	a	faster	rate','with	equal	or	different	rate	depending	upon	the	source	of	alkane']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorinated	isomers	would	result	from	the	reaction	of chlorine	with	n-butane	in	the	presence	of	UV	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorination	products	are	possible	in	the	reaction	of	2,2 dimethylbutane	with	chlorine	in	the	presence	of	ultraviolet	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','3','4','5']
        },
        {
        question: "LPG	(Household	cooking	gas)	is	mainly	a	mixture	of",
        answer: "Butane	+	Isobutane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Methane	+	Ethane','Acetylene	+	O2','Butane	+	Isobutane','Acetylene	+	H2']
        },
        {
        question: "What	type	of	bonding	is	most	important	in	CH3CH2CH2CH2CH2CH3?",
        answer: "covalent",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ionic','hydrogen','covalent','polar']
        },
        {
        question: "Fuel	with	octane	number	90	means	it	is	as	good	as	a	mixture	of	:",
        answer: "90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane','90%	n-Heptane	+	10%	isooctane','	2	Litre	of	90%	isooctane	+	2	litre	of	benzene','	2	Litre	of	90%	n-heptane	+	2	litre	of	benzene']
        },
        {
        question: "In	the	reaction	of	CH3CH2CH=CH2	with	HCl,	the	H	of	the	HCl	will	become attached	to	which	carbon?",
        answer: "C-1",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['C-1','C-2','C-3','C-4']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	react	most	readily	with	bromine	in CCl4?",
        answer: "CH3CH=CH2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','(CH3)3CH','CH3CH=CH2','(CH3)4C']
        },
        {
        question: "A	compound	reacts	with	steam	in	the	presence	of	concentrated	H2SO4	to give	isopropyl	alcohol.	The	compound	could	be",
        answer: "Alkene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Alkane','Alkyne','Alkene','Allene']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	major	product	from	the	acid-catalyzed	hydration	of	2-methyl-2pentene?",
        answer: "2-methyl-2-pentanol",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2-methylpentane','2-methyl-1-pentanol','2-methyl-2-pentanol','2-methyl-3-pentanol']
        },
        {
        question: "What	compound	results	from	the	1,4-addition	of	one	equivalent	of	HBr	to 1,3-butadiene?",
        answer: "1-bromo-2-butene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1-bromo-1-butene','	2-bromo-2-butene','	4-bromo-1-butene','1-bromo-2-butene']
        },
        {
        question: "Rank	the	following	dienes	in	order	of	increasing	stability	: trans-1,	3-pentadiene,	cis-1,3-pentadiene,	1,4-pentadiene	and	1,2-pentadiene.",
        answer: "1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	>	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	distinct	internal	alkynes	exist	with	a	molecular	formula	of C6H10?",
        answer: "3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1','2','3','4']
        },
        {
        question: "	The	higher	reactivity	of	an	alkene	or	alkyne,	as	compared	to	an	alkane,	is due	to",
        answer: "pi	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sigma	bonds','pi	bonds','hydrogen	bonds','None	of	these']
        },
    ]},
    // Semester 1, Geomatic Engineering
    'Elementary Sructures':{
    levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
    programOfStudy: 'Geomatic Engineering',
    semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
    Easy: [
        {
            question: 'A Force is a vector with several components',
            answer: 'True',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'A system of concurrent forces is in static equilibrium if the sum of all the forces is equal to zero and the mass point has acceleration',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'A statically indeterminate pin-jointed frame is a mechanism',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
            
        },
        {
            question: 'A number of forces lying in oone plane are described as concurrent',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'A hinge or pin support allows rotation at the supports',
            answer: 'True',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'Members in Pin-jointed frames carry Bending Moments',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'Shear force(F) and Bending Moments(M) are related by:F=∫M dx',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'A roller support allows movement only in the one direction which is perpendicular to the supporting surface ',
            answer: 'False',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'A reductant frame is statically indeterminate',
            answer: 'True',
            type: 'True/False',
        },
        {
            question: 'SI units of Bending momemt is',
            answer: 'kNm',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['kN/m','kN','kNm','kN/s']
        },
        {
            question: 'What is the other name for positive bending moment?',
            answer: 'Sagging',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['Hogging','Sagging','Inflation','Constraflexure']
        },
    ],
    Medium: [
        {
            question: 'A cantilever beam of span 3m carries a point load 100kN at the mid-span.The magnitude of the mid-span bending moment in the beam will be',
            answer: '6',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['6','300','100','150']
        },
        {
            question: 'The bending moment at the support of beam in the previous question will be',
            answer: '150',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['0','300','100','150']
        },
        {
            question: 'At the point of contraflexure, the value of the bending moment is',
            answer: 'Zero',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['zero','minimum','maximum','cannot be determined']
        },
        {
            question: 'A simply supported beam of length l,(m) carries UDL,of W(kN/m)over the entire span. The mid-span shear force will be ',
            answer: '0',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['W','WL','WL/2','0']
        },
        {
            question: 'What is the mid-span bending moment of the beam in the previous question',
            answer: 'WL^2/8',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['0','WL^2/2','WL^2/4','WL^2/8']
        },
    ],
    Hard: [
        {
            question: 'Shear force at a section in a beam is the algebraic sum of all the vertiacl forces on both sides of the section(right and left) considering the direction of catch force',
            answer: 'A Hinge',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['A Hinge','An Arche','A Truss','A Dam']
        },
        {
            question: 'The form a structure takes depends on the following except',
            answer: 'GPS Location requirements',
            type: 'Multiple Questions',
            options: ['Functional requirements','GPS Location requirement','Material Availability','Foundation requirement']
        },
    ]},
    // Semester 1, Geological Engineering
    'Algebra I' : {
    programOfStudy: "Geological Engineering",
    levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
    semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
    Easy: [
        {
            question: "The set of natural numbers is not closed under multiplication.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The sum of any two irrational numbers is always irrational.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The principle of mathematical induction is used to prove statements for all natural numbers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",   
        },
        {
            question: "If a∙b=0, then a and b must be parallel vectors.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",   
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of a complex number  is given by |z|=√(a^2+b^2 )",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True", 
        },
        {
            question: " The equation x^2+1=0 has no real solution.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: " Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n complex roots.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "The rational number 2/3 is a subset of the set of integers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False", 
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always zero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "If two vectors are orthogonal, their dot product is nonzero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: " Which of the following is an irrational number?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "√2",
            options: ['5/2','3.14','√2','1.5']
        },
        {
            question: "Which property states that a(b+c)=ab+ac ?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Distributive Property",
            options: ['Associative Property','Commutative Property','Distributive Property','Closure Property']
        },
        {
            question: "What is the complex conjugate of 4+3i?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "4-3i",
            options: ['4-3i','-4-3i','4+3i','4,3i']
        },
        {
            question: "The argument of the complex number -3+4i lies in which quadrant?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Second",
            options: ['First','Second','Third','Fourth']
        },
        {
            question: "If a and b are two nonzero vectors, their dot product is given by:",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "|a||b|cos∅",
            options: ['|a||b|sin∅','|a||b|cos∅','|a||b|tan∅','|a|+|b|']
        },
        {
            question: " What is the solution to the equation x^2=-9 in the set of complex numbers?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "±3i",
            options: ['No solution','±3','±3i','±√9']
        },
        {
            question: "If |z|=5 and z=3+bi, what is b?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Both a and b",
            options: ['4','-4','Both a and b','None']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is a unit vector?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "1/√2 i+1/√2 j",
            options: ['3i+4j','5i-2j','i+j','1/√2 i+1/√2 j']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Force",
            options: ['Speed','Temperature','Force','Mass']
        },
       
        {
            question: "The additive inverse of  is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "-7",  
        },
        {
            question: "The square root of -1 is represented by the symbol _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "i",   
        },
        {
            question: "The set of real numbers consists of both rational and _______ numbers.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "irrational", 
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of the complex number 6-8i is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "10",
        },
        {
            question: "The dot product of two perpendicular vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "A vector with a magnitude of 1 is called a _______ vector.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "unit",
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the sum of  3+4i and 2-5i.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "5-i",
        },
        {
            question: " Find the argument of -1+i.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "arctan(-1)+180",
            options: ['arctan(-1)+180','arcsin(-1)+180','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
        {
            question: " Solve for x in 2x+3=7.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the roots of x^2-4x+4=0.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "If z=e^(-i×π/3),express z in rectangular form.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "5/2+(5√3)i/2",
            options: ['5/2+(5√3)i/2','5/2-(√3)i/2','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
    ]},
   'Basic Geology': {
      programOfStudy: 'Geological Engineering',
      levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
      semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
      Easy: [
        { 
        question:"Which of the following materials is believed to have started Solar System?",
        answer: "A swirling gas cloud",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['A swirling gas cloud','Sinking iceberg','A rising dust devil','Convecting magma']
        },
        {
        question: "What percentage of the earth's volume is the mantle?",
        answer: "70%",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['30%','50%','70%','80%']
        },
        {
        question: "Heat transfer through the mantle occurs mostly by",
        answer: "Convection",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Conduction','Convention','Impulse Power','None of these']
        },
        {
        question: "What is the mantle-driven deformation of Earth's rigid exterior called?",
        answer: "Plate tectonics",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Accretion','Mantle rise','Plate tectonics','Mesospheric rise']
        },
        {
        question: "The tendency of some minerals to break along smooth planes",
        answer: "Cleavage",
        type: "Multiple choice",
        options: ['Crystallization','Fracture','Weathering','Cleavage']
        },
        {
        question: "Igneous rocks normally normally have a good engineering properties because of their",
        answer: "Interlocking mineral",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Batholithic nature','Intrusive nature','Interlocking minerals nature','Minerals composition']
        },
        {
        question: "Which property is least reliable in identifying minerals?",
        answer: "Colour",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Hardness','Density','Cleavage','Colour','Fracture']
        },
        {
        question: "The property that causes quartz to break along smoothly curving surfaces:",
        answer: "Fracture",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Hardness','Density','Cleavage','Colour','Fracture']
        },
        {
        question: "All the following can cause metamorphism except",
        answer: "Impact",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Diagenesis','Chemically active and vapor','impact','Temperature']
        },
        {
        question: "Ore minerals are often sulfides and oxides of metallic elements",
        answer: "True",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "Colour and cleavage are two very useful physical properties used to identify quartz",
        answer: "False",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "Igneous rocks formed of igneous debris blown out of a volcano are called pegmatities  ",
        answer: "False",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "The formation of dolostone due to the introduction of magnesium into limestone is an exmaple of diagenesis",
        answer: "True",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "Sedimentary rocks form only at or near Earth's surface never at great depths.",
        answer: "True",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "The sequence of prograde metamorphic change to the protolith shale(a sedimentary rock) is a slate phyllite,gneiss and schist.",
        answer: "False",
        type: "True/False",
        },
        {
        question: "In the chemical-weathering process called oxidation,oxygen must be present to chemically combine with the ions present. ",
        answer: "False",
        type: "True/False", 
        },
        {
        question: "Identify the FALSE statement: The categories of materials that constitute earth include",
        answer: "Organic chemicals;all carbon-containing compounds,including oil,protein,carbon dioxide, and calciim carbonate",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Glasses; solids in which atoms are not in any orderly pattern','Volatiles: materials that easily become gases at ordinary Earth surface tempearture','Organic chemicals;all carbon-containing compounds,including oil,protein,carbon dioxide, and calciim carbonate','Alloys:mixtures of more than one type of metal atom','Melts;solid materials that have melted due to heat']
        },
        {
        question: "Identify the FALSE statement",
        answer: "Magma is the term for very hot rock that is molten;when it cools and hardens it is called lava",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Metamorphic rocks form when pre-existing rocks undergo changes in response to heat and pressure','Hot molten rock that cools and hardens produces igneous rocks','Sedimentary rocks form when pre-existing rock grains get cemented together','Sedimentary rocks form when minearls precipitate out of a out of a solution','Magma is the term for very hot rock that is molten;when it cools and hardens it called lava']
        },
        {
        question: "Identify the FALSE statement in the following.",
        answer: "The crust is the top of the mantle that has cooled and hardened",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['The crust is the top of the mantle that has cooled and hardened','The upper portion of the crust contains microscopic pores that contain groundwater','The crust plus the upper part of the mantle make up the lithosphere','There are two different types of crust:oceanic and continental','The crust-mantle boundary occurs at different depths in different locations']
        },
        {
        question: "Choose the list that shows rock composition and decreasing in silica and increasing in iron and magnesium",
        answer: "Granite,basalt,peridotite",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Granite,peridotite,basalt','Peridotite,basalt,granite','Basalt,Peridotite,Granite','Granite,basalt,Peridotite']
        },
        {
        question: "Magma may cool and freeze to become solid igneous rock",
        answer:"All of the above are ture statements",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['When its dissolved volatiles bubble out','Faster in the presence of circulating groundwater','Wuthin weeks to months,if it intrudes at shallow depth','Very slowly(months to years when it forms a deep pluton','All of the above are true statements']
        },
        {
        question: "What is historical geology concerned with?",
        answer: "Chronology of events",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Processes that operate within the Earth','Materials on which the processes operate','Chronology of events','All of the above']
        },
        {
        question: "Magma typically consists of ........",
        answer: "Molten rock,entrained crystals and vapour",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Only molten rock','Molten rock and entrained crystals','Crystals and vapour','Molten rock,entrained crystals and vapour']
        },
    ], 
      Medium: [
        { 
        question: "Hematite is a mineral with reddish-brown streak and magnetite has...streak",
        answer: "Black", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Brown','Black','Gray','Dull','Conchoidal']
        },
        {
        question: "What is the density of gold?",
        answer: "19.3 g/cm^3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2.5 g/cm^3','5.2 g/cm^3','7.5 g/cm^3','11.2 g/cm^3','19.3 g/cm^3']
        },
        { 
        question: "The least siliceous basaltic magmas contain about 50% SiO2 component whereas the most siliceous magmas contain about ",
        answer: "70%", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60%','40%','70%','30%']
        },
        {
        question: "If magma cools very slowly during crystallization of minerals,the resultant rock is called",
        answer: "Obsidian",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Obsidian','Pegmatite','Feldspathoid','Mineraloid']
        },
        { 
        question: "A volcanic rock with large crystals in a fine-grained groundmass is called a ",
        answer: "Porphry", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Mixite','Largess','Porphry','Phenocryst']
        },
        {
        question: "Granite.....",
        answer: "All of the above",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Is a phaneritic rock','is felsic in compositon','Logically could be found in a batholith','Is the coarse-grained equivalent of rhyolite','All of the above']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which of the following describes the environment in which pumice most likely formed?",
        answer: "Top portion of lava flow", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Top portion of lava flow','Sill-very thin and shallow and intrusive body','Batholith-large,deep intrusive body']
        },
        {
        question: "The sequence of layering of rock at a location can be summarized by drawing",
        answer: "Stratigraphic column",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Structure of rocks','Stratigraphic column','Geological contact','Stratigraphic formations']
        },
        { 
        question: "The liquid component of the earth's asthenosphere is between",
        answer: "1-5%", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1-5%','10-30%','95-99%','35-50%']
        },
        {
        question: "Which of these minerals possesses perfect cleavage?",
        answer:"Muscovite",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Apatite','chhlorite','Muscovite','Graphite']
        },
        { 
        question: "During metamorphism,the process of compactiuon changes the texture of rocks by",
        answer: "All of the above", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Grains moving closer together','Becoming denser','Reducing porosity','All of the above']
        },
        {
        question: "Volcanism and earthquakes are common features along which type of plate boundaries",
        answer: "Divergent plate boundaries",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Divergent plate boundaries','Intransigent plate boundaries','Transform plate boundaries','Convergent plate boundaries']
        },
        { 
        question: "The lithospheric plates that comprise Earth's exterior have three types of contacts between each.These three types are named all of the following except ",
        answer: "Intransient margin", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Divergent margin','Intransient margin','Transient fault margin','Convergent margin']
        },
        {
        question: "The most obvious texture in most metamorphic rocks",
        answer: "Foliation",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Stretched pebbles','Foliation','Lineation','Slaty cleavage']
        },
        { 
        question: "The three dominant diagenetic processes that induce lithification are compaction,cementation and",
        answer: "Recrystallization", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Decay of plant matter','Recrystallization','Orientation']
    
        },
        {
        question: "Physical processes of weathering include all of the following except",
        answer: "Dissolution of calcite",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options:['Frost heaving','Root penetration','Growth of salt crystals','Dissolution of calcite']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which of the following types of rock bodies commonly disobeys the law of superposition?",
        answer: "Sill", 
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Dike','Sill','Conglomerate','Tuff bed']
        },
        {
        question: "The accumulation of matter to form the Earth ",
        answer: "Continues today as meteorites fall",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options:['Ceased 6 billion years ago when the sun was born','Ceased 4.6 billion years ago when the Earth was born','Continues today as meteorites fall','Ceased 65 million years ago when the last dinosaurs dieds']
        },
      ]},
    //   Semester 1, Petrochemical Engineering
    'Algebra 1' : {
    programOfStudy: "Petrochemical Engineering",
    levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
    semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
    Easy: [
        {
            question: "The set of natural numbers is not closed under multiplication.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The sum of any two irrational numbers is always irrational.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The principle of mathematical induction is used to prove statements for all natural numbers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",   
        },
        {
            question: "If a∙b=0, then a and b must be parallel vectors.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",   
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of a complex number  is given by |z|=√(a^2+b^2 )",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True", 
        },
        {
            question: " The equation x^2+1=0 has no real solution.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: " Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n complex roots.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "The rational number 2/3 is a subset of the set of integers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False", 
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always zero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "If two vectors are orthogonal, their dot product is nonzero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: " Which of the following is an irrational number?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "√2",
            options: ['5/2','3.14','√2','1.5']
        },
        {
            question: "Which property states that a(b+c)=ab+ac ?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Distributive Property",
            options: ['Associative Property','Commutative Property','Distributive Property','Closure Property']
        },
        {
            question: "What is the complex conjugate of 4+3i?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "4-3i",
            options: ['4-3i','-4-3i','4+3i','4,3i']
        },
        {
            question: "The argument of the complex number -3+4i lies in which quadrant?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Second",
            options: ['First','Second','Third','Fourth']
        },
        {
            question: "If a and b are two nonzero vectors, their dot product is given by:",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "|a||b|cos∅",
            options: ['|a||b|sin∅','|a||b|cos∅','|a||b|tan∅','|a|+|b|']
        },
        {
            question: " What is the solution to the equation x^2=-9 in the set of complex numbers?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "±3i",
            options: ['No solution','±3','±3i','±√9']
        },
        {
            question: "If |z|=5 and z=3+bi, what is b?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Both a and b",
            options: ['4','-4','Both a and b','None']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is a unit vector?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "1/√2 i+1/√2 j",
            options: ['3i+4j','5i-2j','i+j','1/√2 i+1/√2 j']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Force",
            options: ['Speed','Temperature','Force','Mass']
        },
       
        {
            question: "The additive inverse of  is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "-7",  
        },
        {
            question: "The square root of -1 is represented by the symbol _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "i",   
        },
        {
            question: "The set of real numbers consists of both rational and _______ numbers.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "irrational", 
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of the complex number 6-8i is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "10",
        },
        {
            question: "The dot product of two perpendicular vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "A vector with a magnitude of 1 is called a _______ vector.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "unit",
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the sum of  3+4i and 2-5i.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "5-i",
        },
        {
            question: " Find the argument of -1+i.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "arctan(-1)+180",
            options: ['arctan(-1)+180','arcsin(-1)+180','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
        {
            question: " Solve for x in 2x+3=7.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the roots of x^2-4x+4=0.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "If z=e^(-i×π/3),express z in rectangular form.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "5/2+(5√3)i/2",
            options: ['5/2+(5√3)i/2','5/2-(√3)i/2','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
    ]},
    'Organic Chemistry': {
      programOfStudy: 'Petrochemical Engineering',
      levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
      semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
      Easy: [
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	characteristic	of	organic	compounds?",
        answer: "Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	usually	have	low	melting	points','They	usually	are	only	slightly	soluble	or	insoluble	in	water','If	water	soluble	they	seldom	conduct	an	electric	current.','Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	element	least	likely	to	be	found	in	an	organic	compound	is ......",
        answer: "silicon",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['oxygen','sulfur','nitrogen','silicon']
        },
        { 
        question: "One	of	the	major	sources	of	organic	compounds	is .....",
        answer: "Natural gas",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Natural gas','Fermentation', 'Sea water', 'Atmosphere']
        },
        { 
        question: "Catenation	is	a	property	of	the	carbon	atom	which	describes	its	ability	to ......",
        answer: "bond	with	other	carbon	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bond	with	other	carbon	atoms','form	double	and	triple	bonds', '	exist	in	plant	and	animal	form', 'form	bonds	in	its	ground	state']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	stable	organic	compounds,	carbon	will	always	form ....",
        answer: "4 bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	bonds','4	bonds','3	bonds','5 bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Carbon-carbon	double	bonds	consist	of?",
        answer: "one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond','two σ	bonds,	one	π	bond','one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','two	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Acetylene	has	a	total	of	:",
        answer: "three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','	two	σ	bonds,	four	π	bonds', 'three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds', 'one	σ	bond,	four	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	propene	there	are",
        answer: "eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond','seven	σ	bonds	and	two	π	bonds','six	σ	bonds	and	three	π	bonds','nine	σ	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "1-Buten-3-yne	has",
        answer: "seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['six	σ	and	four	π	bonds','seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds','eight	σ	and	two	π	bonds','nine	σ	and	one	π	bond']
        },
        { 
        question: "Compound	in	which	carbons	use	only	sp3	hybrid	orbitals	for	bond	formation is",
        answer: "CH3CH2CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','CH3C≡CH', 'CH3CH=CH2', 'CH2=CH—CH=CH2']
        },
        { 
        question: "When	the	carbon	atom	is	sp2	hybridized	in	a	compound,	it	is	bonded	to",
        answer: "3	other	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	other	atoms','4	other	atoms', '	3	other	atoms', '5	other	atoms']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	planar	molecule?",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Formaldehyde','Acetone', '	Formic	acid', 'Acetic	acid']
        },
        { 
        question: "	What	is	bond	angle	between	the	hybrid	orbitals	in	methane?",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['180°','	120°', '109.5°', '	115.5°']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–C	bond	angle	in	ethane	is",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','109.5°','120°','118°28']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–H	bond	angle	in	ethylene	is",
        answer: "120°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','120°', '90°', '180°']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	bond	length	of	a	carbon-carbon	double	bond?",
        answer: "1.34	Å",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	1.20	Å','1.34	Å', '	1.54	Å', '1.68	Å']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	lengths	in	rank	of	increasing	bond	length	is	:",
        answer: "triple,	double,	single",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['triple,	double,	single','single,	double,	triple', 'single,	double,	triple', 'triple,	single,	double']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	is	the	correct	order	of	bond	lengths	:",
        answer: "	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C','C–C	>	C≡C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	>	C–C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	<	C–C	>	C=C']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	hydrocarbons	has	the	shortest	C–C	bond	length?",
        answer: "HC≡CH",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','CH3CH3', 'HC≡CH']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	length	is	maximum	in",
        answer: "	CH3CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','	CH3CH3', '	HC≡CH', '']
        },
        { 
        question: "How	many	atoms	are	attached	to	an	atom	having	a	sp	hybridization?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['0','1', '2', '3']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	statement	is	true?",
        answer: "Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Resonance	hybrids	are	inherently	unstable','Resonance	hybrids	are	more	stable	than	any	individual	resonance	form', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	more stable	forms']
        },
        { 
        question: "	....... has same	arrangement	of	atom",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Ethyl	alcohol','Formaldehyde','Diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Resonance	structures	of	a	molecule	have",
        answer: "same	arrangement	of	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['same	arrangement	of	atoms','different	arrangement	of	atoms','different	number	of	paired	electrons','same	number	of	paired	electrons']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	have	planar	molecules?",
        answer: "formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ethyl	alcohol','formaldehyde', 'diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	show	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "cis-1,2-dichloroethylene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['cis-1,2-dichloroethylene','o-dichlorobenzene','trans-1,2-dichloroethylene','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	molecule	has	a	nonzero	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Cl2','CCl4', 'CHCl3','CH4']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons','The	greater	the	number	of	relatively	stable	resonance	contributors,	the	greater is	the	resonance	stabilization.', '	Delocalized	electrons	destabilize	a	compound.']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	correct?",
        answer: "Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	poor	center	to	an	electron rich	center.','A	doubled	headed	arrow	means	one	electron	has	been	moved.','Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.', 'A	single	headed	arrow	means	two	electrons	have	been	moved.']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	does	a	“curved”	arrow	represent?",
        answer: "the	movement	of	two	electron",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['that	two	structures	are	resonance	structures','the	movement	of	two	electron', 'a	link	between	reactants	and	products', 'that	two	structures	are	equivalent']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	predicted	shape,	bond	angle,	and	hybridization	for	CH3+?",
        answer: "trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2','trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp3', '	trigonal	planar,	109.5°,	sp2', '	trigonal	pyramidal,	120°,	sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	name	given	for	a	species	that	contains	a	positively	charged carbon	atom?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	carbanion','carbocation', '	methyl	radical', '	free	radical']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	orbitals	overlap	to	create	the	H–C	bond	in	CH3+",
        answer: "	s–sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	sp3–sp3','sp2–sp3', 's–p', '	s–sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	lone-pair	electrons	of	the	methyl	anion	occupy	a	__________	orbital.",
        answer: "sp3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['s','	sp', 'sp2', 'sp3']
        },
        { 
        question: "An	increase	in	which	of	the	following	results	in	a	decrease	in	the	rate	of	the chemical	reaction?",
        answer: "energy	of	activation",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['temperature','concentration', '	collision	frequency', 'energy	of	activation']
        },
        {
        question: "The	reaction	step	that	has	its	transition	state	at	the	highest	point	on	the reaction	coordinate	is	the	called	the	__________",
        answer: "rate-determining	step",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rate-determining	step','activation	energy','transition	step','	product	favored	step']
        },
        {
        question: "An	electrophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	a	nucleophile",
        answer: "Lewis	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	base','Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','	Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "A	nucleophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	an	electrophile",
        answer: "Lewis	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','	Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','Lewis	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	normally	considered	to	be	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "CH3CH2+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['NH3','CH3NH2','HC≡C:','CH3CH2+']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "FeBr3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['FeBr3','	Br','	NH3','	CH3OCH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	the	strongest	interaction?",
        answer: "	a	covalent	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	a	covalent	bond','dipole-dipole	interactions','	hydrogen	bonding','van	der	Waals']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Electrons	move	toward	positively	charged	locations.','	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.','	An	electrophile	is	electron	loving.','	A	nucleophile	has	a	a	pair	of	electrons	it	can	share.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	nonpolar	molecule?",
        answer: "H2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	HCl','CH3Cl','H2','NH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	is	defined	as	a	species	that	accepts	a	proton?",
        answer: "Bronsted-Lowry	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Lewis	acid','Lewis	base','	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct?",
        answer: "The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	base,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	acid.']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	conjugate	acid	of	CH3NH2?",
        answer: "CH3NH3+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3NH3+','CH3NH','	NH4+','NH2-']
        },
        {
        question: "A	molecule	is	said	to	be	chiral",
        answer: "	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	if	it	contains	plane	of	symmetry','if	it	contains	centre	of	symmetry','	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image','if	it	can	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	false	regarding	chiral	compounds?",
        answer: "have	cis	and	trans	isomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','have	cis	and	trans	isomers','	exist	as	enantiomers','	can	be	detected	with	a	polarimeter']
        },
        {
        question: "An	optically	active	compound",
        answer: "when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	must	contain	atleast	four	carbons','when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','	must	always	contain	an	asymmetric	carbon	atom','	in	solution	always	give	a	negative	reading	in	polarimeter.']
        },
        {
        question: "Plane-polarized	light	is	affected	by",
        answer: "Chiral	molecules",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['dentical	molecules','All	polymers','Chiral	molecules','All	biomolecules']
        },
        {
        question: "It	is	possible	to	distinguish	between	optical	isomers",
        answer: "by	polarimetry",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['by	using	chemical	tests','by	mass	spectrometry','by	IR	spectroscopy','by	polarimetry']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	mirror	images	are	called	:",
        answer: "Enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Tautomers','Diastereomers','Enantiomers','	Metamers']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	not	mirror	images	are	called",
        answer: "Diastereomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Diastereomers','	Enantiomers','Metamers','	Meso	compounds']
        },
        {
        question: "Enantiomers	have	which	of	the	following	characteristics?",
        answer: "have	the	same	melting	point",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	ordinary	light','have	the	same	melting	point','are	superimposable	mirror	images','react	with	optically	active	molecules	at	the	same	rate']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	false	about	enantiomers?",
        answer: "are	superimposable	mirror	images",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	plane-polarized	light','are	superimposable	mirror	images','are	nonsuperimposable	mirror	images','have	the	same	melting	point']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	possible	number	of	optical	isomers	for	a	compound	containing 2	dissimilar	asymmetric	carbon	atoms?",
        answer: "4",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "Meso-Tartaric	acid	is",
        answer: "always	optically	inactive",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sometimes	optically	active','always	optically	active','sometimes	optically	inactive','always	optically	inactive']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "2-Chloropropanoic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Propanoic	acid','	3-Chloropropanoic	acid','2-Chloropropanoic	acid','3-Chloropropene']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "	Lactic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Succinic	acid','	meso-Tartaric	acid','	Lactic	acid','Chloroacetic	acid']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct	concerning	a	pair	of enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and in	opposite	directions','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and	in	the	same direction','	They	have	different	melting	points']
        },
        {
        question: "A	and	B	are	stereoisomers.	They	are	nonsuperimposable	and	are	mirror images	of	one	another.	Which	of	the	following	best	describes	the	relationship between	A	and	B",
        answer: "enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['structural	isomers','enantiomers','cis-trans	isomers','diastereomers']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	true	of	enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	have	the	same	melting	point.','	They	have	the	same	boiling	point.','	They	have	the	same	density.','They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	correct	about	diastereomers?",
        answer: "	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.','	They	are	a	pair	of	identical	isomers.','They	are	a	pair	of	isomers	that	are	mirror	images.','All	their	asymmetric	centers	are	the	same.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is/are	optically	inactive?",
        answer: "all	the	above",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['50-50	mixture	of	R	and	S	enantiomers','a	meso	compound','a	racemic	mixture','all	the	above']
        },
        {
        question: "Hydrocarbons	are",
        answer: "both	(a)	and	(b)",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['insoluble	in	water','composed	of	carbon	and	hydrogen','both	(a)	and	(b)','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	hexane?",
        answer: "5",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['4','5','6','7']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	heptane",
        answer: "9",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['9','10','11','12']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	reactions	can	be	used	to	prepare	alkanes?",
        answer: "	Corey-House	synthesis",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Corey-House	synthesis','Williamson	synthesis','Friedel-Crafts	reactions','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "What	product	is	formed	in	the	free-radical	bromination	of	methane?",
        answer: "all	of	these",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bromomethane','dibromomethane','	tribromomethane','all	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "Chlorination	of	an	alkane	as	compared	to	bromination	proceeds",
        answer: "at	a	faster	rate",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['at	a	slower	rate','with	equal	rates','at	a	faster	rate','with	equal	or	different	rate	depending	upon	the	source	of	alkane']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorinated	isomers	would	result	from	the	reaction	of chlorine	with	n-butane	in	the	presence	of	UV	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorination	products	are	possible	in	the	reaction	of	2,2 dimethylbutane	with	chlorine	in	the	presence	of	ultraviolet	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','3','4','5']
        },
        {
        question: "LPG	(Household	cooking	gas)	is	mainly	a	mixture	of",
        answer: "Butane	+	Isobutane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Methane	+	Ethane','Acetylene	+	O2','Butane	+	Isobutane','Acetylene	+	H2']
        },
        {
        question: "What	type	of	bonding	is	most	important	in	CH3CH2CH2CH2CH2CH3?",
        answer: "covalent",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ionic','hydrogen','covalent','polar']
        },
        {
        question: "Fuel	with	octane	number	90	means	it	is	as	good	as	a	mixture	of	:",
        answer: "90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane','90%	n-Heptane	+	10%	isooctane','	2	Litre	of	90%	isooctane	+	2	litre	of	benzene','	2	Litre	of	90%	n-heptane	+	2	litre	of	benzene']
        },
        {
        question: "In	the	reaction	of	CH3CH2CH=CH2	with	HCl,	the	H	of	the	HCl	will	become attached	to	which	carbon?",
        answer: "C-1",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['C-1','C-2','C-3','C-4']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	react	most	readily	with	bromine	in CCl4?",
        answer: "CH3CH=CH2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','(CH3)3CH','CH3CH=CH2','(CH3)4C']
        },
        {
        question: "A	compound	reacts	with	steam	in	the	presence	of	concentrated	H2SO4	to give	isopropyl	alcohol.	The	compound	could	be",
        answer: "Alkene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Alkane','Alkyne','Alkene','Allene']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	major	product	from	the	acid-catalyzed	hydration	of	2-methyl-2pentene?",
        answer: "2-methyl-2-pentanol",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2-methylpentane','2-methyl-1-pentanol','2-methyl-2-pentanol','2-methyl-3-pentanol']
        },
        {
        question: "What	compound	results	from	the	1,4-addition	of	one	equivalent	of	HBr	to 1,3-butadiene?",
        answer: "1-bromo-2-butene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1-bromo-1-butene','	2-bromo-2-butene','	4-bromo-1-butene','1-bromo-2-butene']
        },
        {
        question: "Rank	the	following	dienes	in	order	of	increasing	stability	: trans-1,	3-pentadiene,	cis-1,3-pentadiene,	1,4-pentadiene	and	1,2-pentadiene.",
        answer: "1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	>	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	distinct	internal	alkynes	exist	with	a	molecular	formula	of C6H10?",
        answer: "3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1','2','3','4']
        },
        {
        question: "	The	higher	reactivity	of	an	alkene	or	alkyne,	as	compared	to	an	alkane,	is due	to",
        answer: "pi	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sigma	bonds','pi	bonds','hydrogen	bonds','None	of	these']
        },
    ]},
    // Semester 1, Petroleum Engineering
    'ALGEBRA' : {
    programOfStudy: "Petroleum Engineering",
    levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
    semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
    Easy: [
        {
            question: "The set of natural numbers is not closed under multiplication.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The sum of any two irrational numbers is always irrational.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The principle of mathematical induction is used to prove statements for all natural numbers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",   
        },
        {
            question: "If a∙b=0, then a and b must be parallel vectors.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",   
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of a complex number  is given by |z|=√(a^2+b^2 )",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True", 
        },
        {
            question: " The equation x^2+1=0 has no real solution.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: " Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n complex roots.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "The rational number 2/3 is a subset of the set of integers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False", 
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always zero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "If two vectors are orthogonal, their dot product is nonzero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: " Which of the following is an irrational number?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "√2",
            options: ['5/2','3.14','√2','1.5']
        },
        {
            question: "Which property states that a(b+c)=ab+ac ?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Distributive Property",
            options: ['Associative Property','Commutative Property','Distributive Property','Closure Property']
        },
        {
            question: "What is the complex conjugate of 4+3i?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "4-3i",
            options: ['4-3i','-4-3i','4+3i','4,3i']
        },
        {
            question: "The argument of the complex number -3+4i lies in which quadrant?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Second",
            options: ['First','Second','Third','Fourth']
        },
        {
            question: "If a and b are two nonzero vectors, their dot product is given by:",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "|a||b|cos∅",
            options: ['|a||b|sin∅','|a||b|cos∅','|a||b|tan∅','|a|+|b|']
        },
        {
            question: " What is the solution to the equation x^2=-9 in the set of complex numbers?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "±3i",
            options: ['No solution','±3','±3i','±√9']
        },
        {
            question: "If |z|=5 and z=3+bi, what is b?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Both a and b",
            options: ['4','-4','Both a and b','None']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is a unit vector?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "1/√2 i+1/√2 j",
            options: ['3i+4j','5i-2j','i+j','1/√2 i+1/√2 j']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Force",
            options: ['Speed','Temperature','Force','Mass']
        },
       
        {
            question: "The additive inverse of  is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "-7",  
        },
        {
            question: "The square root of -1 is represented by the symbol _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "i",   
        },
        {
            question: "The set of real numbers consists of both rational and _______ numbers.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "irrational", 
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of the complex number 6-8i is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "10",
        },
        {
            question: "The dot product of two perpendicular vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "A vector with a magnitude of 1 is called a _______ vector.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "unit",
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the sum of  3+4i and 2-5i.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "5-i",
        },
        {
            question: " Find the argument of -1+i.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "arctan(-1)+180",
            options: ['arctan(-1)+180','arcsin(-1)+180','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
        {
            question: " Solve for x in 2x+3=7.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the roots of x^2-4x+4=0.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "If z=e^(-i×π/3),express z in rectangular form.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "5/2+(5√3)i/2",
            options: ['5/2+(5√3)i/2','5/2-(√3)i/2','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
    ]},
    'Organic Chemistry For Engineers': {
      programOfStudy: 'Petroleum Engineering',
      levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
      semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
      Easy: [
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	characteristic	of	organic	compounds?",
        answer: "Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	usually	have	low	melting	points','They	usually	are	only	slightly	soluble	or	insoluble	in	water','If	water	soluble	they	seldom	conduct	an	electric	current.','Bonds which bind the atoms together are nearly always ionic']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	element	least	likely	to	be	found	in	an	organic	compound	is ......",
        answer: "silicon",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['oxygen','sulfur','nitrogen','silicon']
        },
        { 
        question: "One	of	the	major	sources	of	organic	compounds	is .....",
        answer: "Natural gas",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Natural gas','Fermentation', 'Sea water', 'Atmosphere']
        },
        { 
        question: "Catenation	is	a	property	of	the	carbon	atom	which	describes	its	ability	to ......",
        answer: "bond	with	other	carbon	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bond	with	other	carbon	atoms','form	double	and	triple	bonds', '	exist	in	plant	and	animal	form', 'form	bonds	in	its	ground	state']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	stable	organic	compounds,	carbon	will	always	form ....",
        answer: "4 bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	bonds','4	bonds','3	bonds','5 bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Carbon-carbon	double	bonds	consist	of?",
        answer: "one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['one	σ	bond,	one	π	bond','two σ	bonds,	one	π	bond','one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','two	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "Acetylene	has	a	total	of	:",
        answer: "three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	one	σ	bond,	two	π	bonds','	two	σ	bonds,	four	π	bonds', 'three	σ	bonds,	two	π	bonds', 'one	σ	bond,	four	π	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "In	propene	there	are",
        answer: "eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['eight	σ	bonds	and	one	π	bond','seven	σ	bonds	and	two	π	bonds','six	σ	bonds	and	three	π	bonds','nine	σ	bonds']
        },
        { 
        question: "1-Buten-3-yne	has",
        answer: "seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['six	σ	and	four	π	bonds','seven	σ	and	three	π	bonds','eight	σ	and	two	π	bonds','nine	σ	and	one	π	bond']
        },
        { 
        question: "Compound	in	which	carbons	use	only	sp3	hybrid	orbitals	for	bond	formation is",
        answer: "CH3CH2CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','CH3C≡CH', 'CH3CH=CH2', 'CH2=CH—CH=CH2']
        },
        { 
        question: "When	the	carbon	atom	is	sp2	hybridized	in	a	compound,	it	is	bonded	to",
        answer: "3	other	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2	other	atoms','4	other	atoms', '	3	other	atoms', '5	other	atoms']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	planar	molecule?",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Formaldehyde','Acetone', '	Formic	acid', 'Acetic	acid']
        },
        { 
        question: "	What	is	bond	angle	between	the	hybrid	orbitals	in	methane?",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['180°','	120°', '109.5°', '	115.5°']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–C	bond	angle	in	ethane	is",
        answer: "109.5°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','109.5°','120°','118°28']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	H–C–H	bond	angle	in	ethylene	is",
        answer: "120°",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['60°','120°', '90°', '180°']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	bond	length	of	a	carbon-carbon	double	bond?",
        answer: "1.34	Å",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	1.20	Å','1.34	Å', '	1.54	Å', '1.68	Å']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	lengths	in	rank	of	increasing	bond	length	is	:",
        answer: "triple,	double,	single",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['triple,	double,	single','single,	double,	triple', 'single,	double,	triple', 'triple,	single,	double']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	is	the	correct	order	of	bond	lengths	:",
        answer: "	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	C–C	<	C=C	<	C≡C','C–C	>	C≡C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	>	C–C	>	C=C', '	C≡C	<	C–C	>	C=C']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	hydrocarbons	has	the	shortest	C–C	bond	length?",
        answer: "HC≡CH",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','CH3CH3', 'HC≡CH']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	carbon-carbon	bond	length	is	maximum	in",
        answer: "	CH3CH3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH2=CH2','	CH3CH3', '	HC≡CH', '']
        },
        { 
        question: "How	many	atoms	are	attached	to	an	atom	having	a	sp	hybridization?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['0','1', '2', '3']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	statement	is	true?",
        answer: "Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Resonance	hybrids	are	inherently	unstable','Resonance	hybrids	are	more	stable	than	any	individual	resonance	form', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	less stable	forms.', 'Resonance	hybrids	are	averages	of	all	resonance	forms	resembling	the	more stable	forms']
        },
        { 
        question: "	....... has same	arrangement	of	atom",
        answer: "Formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Ethyl	alcohol','Formaldehyde','Diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Resonance	structures	of	a	molecule	have",
        answer: "same	arrangement	of	atoms",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['same	arrangement	of	atoms','different	arrangement	of	atoms','different	number	of	paired	electrons','same	number	of	paired	electrons']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	have	planar	molecules?",
        answer: "formaldehyde",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ethyl	alcohol','formaldehyde', 'diethyl	ether','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "	Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	show	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "cis-1,2-dichloroethylene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['cis-1,2-dichloroethylene','o-dichlorobenzene','trans-1,2-dichloroethylene','p-dichlorobenzene']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	molecule	has	a	nonzero	dipole	moment?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Cl2','CCl4', 'CHCl3','CH4']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Resonance	stabilization	is	the	extra	stability	a	compound	gains	from	having delocalized	electrons','The	greater	the	number	of	relatively	stable	resonance	contributors,	the	greater is	the	resonance	stabilization.', '	Delocalized	electrons	destabilize	a	compound.']
        },
        { 
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	correct?",
        answer: "Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	poor	center	to	an	electron rich	center.','A	doubled	headed	arrow	means	one	electron	has	been	moved.','Curved	arrows	are	always	drawn	from	an	electron	rich	center	to	an	electron poor	center.', 'A	single	headed	arrow	means	two	electrons	have	been	moved.']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	does	a	“curved”	arrow	represent?",
        answer: "the	movement	of	two	electron",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['that	two	structures	are	resonance	structures','the	movement	of	two	electron', 'a	link	between	reactants	and	products', 'that	two	structures	are	equivalent']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	predicted	shape,	bond	angle,	and	hybridization	for	CH3+?",
        answer: "trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp2','trigonal	planar,	120°,	sp3', '	trigonal	planar,	109.5°,	sp2', '	trigonal	pyramidal,	120°,	sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	is	the	name	given	for	a	species	that	contains	a	positively	charged carbon	atom?",
        answer: "",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	carbanion','carbocation', '	methyl	radical', '	free	radical']
        },
        { 
        question: "What	orbitals	overlap	to	create	the	H–C	bond	in	CH3+",
        answer: "	s–sp2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	sp3–sp3','sp2–sp3', 's–p', '	s–sp2']
        },
        { 
        question: "The	lone-pair	electrons	of	the	methyl	anion	occupy	a	__________	orbital.",
        answer: "sp3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['s','	sp', 'sp2', 'sp3']
        },
        { 
        question: "An	increase	in	which	of	the	following	results	in	a	decrease	in	the	rate	of	the chemical	reaction?",
        answer: "energy	of	activation",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['temperature','concentration', '	collision	frequency', 'energy	of	activation']
        },
        {
        question: "The	reaction	step	that	has	its	transition	state	at	the	highest	point	on	the reaction	coordinate	is	the	called	the	__________",
        answer: "rate-determining	step",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rate-determining	step','activation	energy','transition	step','	product	favored	step']
        },
        {
        question: "An	electrophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	a	nucleophile",
        answer: "Lewis	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	base','Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','	Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "A	nucleophile	acts	as	a	__________	when	it	reacts	with	an	electrophile",
        answer: "Lewis	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','	Arrhenius	base','Lewis	acid','Lewis	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	normally	considered	to	be	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "CH3CH2+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['NH3','CH3NH2','HC≡C:','CH3CH2+']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	a	nucleophile?",
        answer: "FeBr3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['FeBr3','	Br','	NH3','	CH3OCH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	the	strongest	interaction?",
        answer: "	a	covalent	bond",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	a	covalent	bond','dipole-dipole	interactions','	hydrogen	bonding','van	der	Waals']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	incorrect?",
        answer: "	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	Electrons	move	toward	positively	charged	locations.','	An	electron-rich	atom	is	called	an	electrophile.','	An	electrophile	is	electron	loving.','	A	nucleophile	has	a	a	pair	of	electrons	it	can	share.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	a	nonpolar	molecule?",
        answer: "H2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	HCl','CH3Cl','H2','NH3']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	is	defined	as	a	species	that	accepts	a	proton?",
        answer: "Bronsted-Lowry	base",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Lewis	acid','Lewis	base','	Bronsted-Lowry	acid','Bronsted-Lowry	base']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct?",
        answer: "The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	base.','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	base,	the	stronger	its	conjugate	base','The	stronger	the	acid,	the	weaker	its	conjugate	acid.']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	conjugate	acid	of	CH3NH2?",
        answer: "CH3NH3+",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3NH3+','CH3NH','	NH4+','NH2-']
        },
        {
        question: "A	molecule	is	said	to	be	chiral",
        answer: "	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	if	it	contains	plane	of	symmetry','if	it	contains	centre	of	symmetry','	if	it	cannot	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image','if	it	can	be	superimposed	on	its	mirror	image']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	false	regarding	chiral	compounds?",
        answer: "have	cis	and	trans	isomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','have	cis	and	trans	isomers','	exist	as	enantiomers','	can	be	detected	with	a	polarimeter']
        },
        {
        question: "An	optically	active	compound",
        answer: "when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	must	contain	atleast	four	carbons','when	in	solution	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light','	must	always	contain	an	asymmetric	carbon	atom','	in	solution	always	give	a	negative	reading	in	polarimeter.']
        },
        {
        question: "Plane-polarized	light	is	affected	by",
        answer: "Chiral	molecules",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['dentical	molecules','All	polymers','Chiral	molecules','All	biomolecules']
        },
        {
        question: "It	is	possible	to	distinguish	between	optical	isomers",
        answer: "by	polarimetry",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['by	using	chemical	tests','by	mass	spectrometry','by	IR	spectroscopy','by	polarimetry']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	mirror	images	are	called	:",
        answer: "Enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Tautomers','Diastereomers','Enantiomers','	Metamers']
        },
        {
        question: "Optical	isomers	that	are	not	mirror	images	are	called",
        answer: "Diastereomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Diastereomers','	Enantiomers','Metamers','	Meso	compounds']
        },
        {
        question: "Enantiomers	have	which	of	the	following	characteristics?",
        answer: "have	the	same	melting	point",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	ordinary	light','have	the	same	melting	point','are	superimposable	mirror	images','react	with	optically	active	molecules	at	the	same	rate']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	false	about	enantiomers?",
        answer: "are	superimposable	mirror	images",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['rotate	plane-polarized	light','are	superimposable	mirror	images','are	nonsuperimposable	mirror	images','have	the	same	melting	point']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	possible	number	of	optical	isomers	for	a	compound	containing 2	dissimilar	asymmetric	carbon	atoms?",
        answer: "4",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "Meso-Tartaric	acid	is",
        answer: "always	optically	inactive",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sometimes	optically	active','always	optically	active','sometimes	optically	inactive','always	optically	inactive']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "2-Chloropropanoic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Propanoic	acid','	3-Chloropropanoic	acid','2-Chloropropanoic	acid','3-Chloropropene']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	be	optically	active?",
        answer: "	Lactic	acid",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Succinic	acid','	meso-Tartaric	acid','	Lactic	acid','Chloroacetic	acid']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	statements	is	correct	concerning	a	pair	of enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	exactly	the	same	amount	and	in opposite	directions.','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and in	opposite	directions','	They	rotate	the	plane	of	polarized	light	by	differing	amounts	and	in	the	same direction','	They	have	different	melting	points']
        },
        {
        question: "A	and	B	are	stereoisomers.	They	are	nonsuperimposable	and	are	mirror images	of	one	another.	Which	of	the	following	best	describes	the	relationship between	A	and	B",
        answer: "enantiomers",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['structural	isomers','enantiomers','cis-trans	isomers','diastereomers']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is	not	true	of	enantiomers?",
        answer: "They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['They	have	the	same	melting	point.','	They	have	the	same	boiling	point.','	They	have	the	same	density.','They	have	the	same	specific	rotation.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	statements	is	correct	about	diastereomers?",
        answer: "	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['	They	are	stereoisomers	that	are	not	enantiomers.','	They	are	a	pair	of	identical	isomers.','They	are	a	pair	of	isomers	that	are	mirror	images.','All	their	asymmetric	centers	are	the	same.']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	is/are	optically	inactive?",
        answer: "all	the	above",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['50-50	mixture	of	R	and	S	enantiomers','a	meso	compound','a	racemic	mixture','all	the	above']
        },
        {
        question: "Hydrocarbons	are",
        answer: "both	(a)	and	(b)",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['insoluble	in	water','composed	of	carbon	and	hydrogen','both	(a)	and	(b)','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	hexane?",
        answer: "5",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['4','5','6','7']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	isomers	are	possible	for	heptane",
        answer: "9",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['9','10','11','12']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	reactions	can	be	used	to	prepare	alkanes?",
        answer: "	Corey-House	synthesis",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Corey-House	synthesis','Williamson	synthesis','Friedel-Crafts	reactions','None	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "What	product	is	formed	in	the	free-radical	bromination	of	methane?",
        answer: "all	of	these",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['bromomethane','dibromomethane','	tribromomethane','all	of	these']
        },
        {
        question: "Chlorination	of	an	alkane	as	compared	to	bromination	proceeds",
        answer: "at	a	faster	rate",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['at	a	slower	rate','with	equal	rates','at	a	faster	rate','with	equal	or	different	rate	depending	upon	the	source	of	alkane']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorinated	isomers	would	result	from	the	reaction	of chlorine	with	n-butane	in	the	presence	of	UV	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','4','6','8']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	monochlorination	products	are	possible	in	the	reaction	of	2,2 dimethylbutane	with	chlorine	in	the	presence	of	ultraviolet	light?",
        answer: "2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2','3','4','5']
        },
        {
        question: "LPG	(Household	cooking	gas)	is	mainly	a	mixture	of",
        answer: "Butane	+	Isobutane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Methane	+	Ethane','Acetylene	+	O2','Butane	+	Isobutane','Acetylene	+	H2']
        },
        {
        question: "What	type	of	bonding	is	most	important	in	CH3CH2CH2CH2CH2CH3?",
        answer: "covalent",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['ionic','hydrogen','covalent','polar']
        },
        {
        question: "Fuel	with	octane	number	90	means	it	is	as	good	as	a	mixture	of	:",
        answer: "90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['90%	Isooctane	+	10%	n-heptane','90%	n-Heptane	+	10%	isooctane','	2	Litre	of	90%	isooctane	+	2	litre	of	benzene','	2	Litre	of	90%	n-heptane	+	2	litre	of	benzene']
        },
        {
        question: "In	the	reaction	of	CH3CH2CH=CH2	with	HCl,	the	H	of	the	HCl	will	become attached	to	which	carbon?",
        answer: "C-1",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['C-1','C-2','C-3','C-4']
        },
        {
        question: "Which	of	the	following	compounds	will	react	most	readily	with	bromine	in CCl4?",
        answer: "CH3CH=CH2",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['CH3CH2CH3','(CH3)3CH','CH3CH=CH2','(CH3)4C']
        },
        {
        question: "A	compound	reacts	with	steam	in	the	presence	of	concentrated	H2SO4	to give	isopropyl	alcohol.	The	compound	could	be",
        answer: "Alkene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['Alkane','Alkyne','Alkene','Allene']
        },
        {
        question: "What	is	the	major	product	from	the	acid-catalyzed	hydration	of	2-methyl-2pentene?",
        answer: "2-methyl-2-pentanol",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['2-methylpentane','2-methyl-1-pentanol','2-methyl-2-pentanol','2-methyl-3-pentanol']
        },
        {
        question: "What	compound	results	from	the	1,4-addition	of	one	equivalent	of	HBr	to 1,3-butadiene?",
        answer: "1-bromo-2-butene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1-bromo-1-butene','	2-bromo-2-butene','	4-bromo-1-butene','1-bromo-2-butene']
        },
        {
        question: "Rank	the	following	dienes	in	order	of	increasing	stability	: trans-1,	3-pentadiene,	cis-1,3-pentadiene,	1,4-pentadiene	and	1,2-pentadiene.",
        answer: "1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	<	1,4-pentadiene	<	cis-1,3-pentadiene	>	trans-1,3 pentadiene','1,2-pentadiene	>	1,4-pentadiene	>	cis-1,3-pentadiene	<	trans-1,3 pentadiene']
        },
        {
        question: "How	many	distinct	internal	alkynes	exist	with	a	molecular	formula	of C6H10?",
        answer: "3",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['1','2','3','4']
        },
        {
        question: "	The	higher	reactivity	of	an	alkene	or	alkyne,	as	compared	to	an	alkane,	is due	to",
        answer: "pi	bonds",
        type: "Multiple Choice",
        options: ['sigma	bonds','pi	bonds','hydrogen	bonds','None	of	these']
        },
    ]},
    // Semester 1, Civil Engineering
    'ALGEBRA I' : {
    programOfStudy: "Civil Engineering",
    levelOfStudy: "Level 100",
    semesterOfStudy: "Semester 1",
    Easy: [
        {
            question: "The set of natural numbers is not closed under multiplication.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The sum of any two irrational numbers is always irrational.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: "The principle of mathematical induction is used to prove statements for all natural numbers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",   
        },
        {
            question: "If a∙b=0, then a and b must be parallel vectors.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",   
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of a complex number  is given by |z|=√(a^2+b^2 )",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True", 
        },
        {
            question: " The equation x^2+1=0 has no real solution.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: " Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n complex roots.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "The rational number 2/3 is a subset of the set of integers.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False", 
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always zero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "True",
        },
        {
            question: "If two vectors are orthogonal, their dot product is nonzero.",
            type: "True/False",
            answer: "False",
        },
        {
            question: " Which of the following is an irrational number?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "√2",
            options: ['5/2','3.14','√2','1.5']
        },
        {
            question: "Which property states that a(b+c)=ab+ac ?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Distributive Property",
            options: ['Associative Property','Commutative Property','Distributive Property','Closure Property']
        },
        {
            question: "What is the complex conjugate of 4+3i?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "4-3i",
            options: ['4-3i','-4-3i','4+3i','4,3i']
        },
        {
            question: "The argument of the complex number -3+4i lies in which quadrant?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Second",
            options: ['First','Second','Third','Fourth']
        },
        {
            question: "If a and b are two nonzero vectors, their dot product is given by:",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "|a||b|cos∅",
            options: ['|a||b|sin∅','|a||b|cos∅','|a||b|tan∅','|a|+|b|']
        },
        {
            question: " What is the solution to the equation x^2=-9 in the set of complex numbers?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "±3i",
            options: ['No solution','±3','±3i','±√9']
        },
        {
            question: "If |z|=5 and z=3+bi, what is b?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Both a and b",
            options: ['4','-4','Both a and b','None']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is a unit vector?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "1/√2 i+1/√2 j",
            options: ['3i+4j','5i-2j','i+j','1/√2 i+1/√2 j']
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity?",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "Force",
            options: ['Speed','Temperature','Force','Mass']
        },
       
        {
            question: "The additive inverse of  is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "-7",  
        },
        {
            question: "The square root of -1 is represented by the symbol _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "i",   
        },
        {
            question: "The set of real numbers consists of both rational and _______ numbers.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "irrational", 
        },
        {
            question: "The modulus of the complex number 6-8i is _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "10",
        },
        {
            question: "The dot product of two perpendicular vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "A vector with a magnitude of 1 is called a _______ vector.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "unit",
        },
        {
            question: "The cross product of two parallel vectors is always _______.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "zero",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the sum of  3+4i and 2-5i.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "5-i",
        },
        {
            question: " Find the argument of -1+i.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "arctan(-1)+180",
            options: ['arctan(-1)+180','arcsin(-1)+180','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
        {
            question: " Solve for x in 2x+3=7.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "Find the roots of x^2-4x+4=0.",
            type: "Fill-in",
            answer: "2",
        },
        {
            question: "If z=e^(-i×π/3),express z in rectangular form.",
            type: "Multiple Choice",
            answer: "5/2+(5√3)i/2",
            options: ['5/2+(5√3)i/2','5/2-(√3)i/2','3/2-(5√3)i','1/2+(5√3)/2']
        },
    ]},
    'Environmental Studies':{
        levelOfStudy: 'Level 100',
        programOfStudy: 'Civil Engineering',
        semesterOfStudy: 'Semester 1',
        Easy: [
            {
                question: 'In the hydrological cycle, the visible phenomena include:',
                answer: 'Transport by wind',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Absorption','Transport by wind','Water vapour',' Underground flow']
            },
            {
                question: ' The icebergs and polar ice constitute ___ of the water ice incidence on Earth.',
                answer: '2.13%',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['80%','2.13%','4%','6.13%','0.60%']
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of these elements are not considered as influential elements that promote eutrophication in water bodies?',
                answer: 'Sulphates, Iron, and Manganese',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Sulphates, Iron, and Manganese','Ammonium, Phosphorus, and Sodium','Nitrates, Silica, and Iron','Manganese, Phosphorus, and Silica']
            },
            {
                question: 'In the gravimetric method for the determination of suspended solids in a water sample, the value of total suspended solids is obtained by:',
                answer: 'Filtration, drying at 105°C, and weighing the crude material',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Filtration and titration with 0.02N H₂SO₄','Filtration, spectrophotometric analysis, and weighing the material','Filtration, drying at 105°C, and weighing the crude material','Filtration, jar test, and weighing the material precipitated']
            },
            {
                question: 'In a residential area, the level of acceptable noise pollution is given as:',
                answer: '60 decibels',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['80 decibels','60 decibels','42 TON','60 TON']
            },
            {
                question: 'In evaluating the odor and taste of a water sample:',
                answer: 'A panel of judges is employed and the sample serially diluted',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['The Lovibond comparator is used','The Nesslerizer is used','A panel of judges is employed and the sample serially diluted','A serial dilution method is adopted and the mixture is analyzed with the Lovibond']
            },
            {
                question: 'The following are for remedying greenhouse effects except',
                answer: 'Grazing of cattle',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Afforestation','Utilization of fossil fuel as efficiently as possible','Utilization of renewable energy systems','Grazing of cattle']
            },
            {
                question: 'The difference between recycling and re-use is that in re-use',
                answer: 'The products are not processed',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['The products are not processed','Pre-fabricated units are not done','Products are used over and over again','Products are not used again in their original form']
            },
            {
                question: 'Diseases whose causative pathogens spend part of their life cycle in an aquatic organism are referred to as:',
                answer: 'Water-based diseases',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Water-based diseases','Water-borne diseases','Water insect vector diseases','Aquatic-based diseases']
            },
            {
                question: 'The coliforms are a group of microorganisms that are:',
                answer: 'Aerobes or facultative aerobes, gram-negative, and metabolize lactose',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Aerobes or facultative aerobes, gram-negative, and pathogenic','Aerobes or facultative aerobes, metabolize lactose, and gram-positive','Aerobes or facultative aerobes, gram-negative, and metabolize lactose','Aerobes or facultative aerobes, gram-negative, and thrive as thermophiles']
            },
            {
                question: 'Viral infections are in general prominent and difficult to control because',
                answer: 'Multiplication of the virus is coupled with the metabolic processes, e.g., nucleic acid synthesis of the host cell',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Multiplication of the virus is coupled with the metabolic processes, e.g., nucleic acid synthesis of the host cell','Viruses are too small organisms to be targeted by antibiotics','Viruses comprise DNA or RNA covered by a protein coat','Viruses need only nucleic acid for their reproduction']
            },
            {
                question: 'In the infectious cycle of schistosomiasis, the causative parasite that lives and develops in the veins and arteries of the human host is called:',
                answer: 'Cercaria',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Plasmodium','Miracidia','Cercaria','Millipede']
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of these are water-based diseases?',
                answer: 'Guinea worm and Schistosomiasis',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Leprosy, Guinea worm','Malaria, Guinea worm','Guinea worm and Schistosomiasis','Schistosomiasis and Malaria']
            },
            {
                question: 'LD-50 is defined as the amount of compound:',
                answer: 'Which when ingested once could result in the death of 50% of its consumers within a period of 96 hours',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Which when ingested once could result in the death of 50 people within a period of 4 days','Which when ingested once could result in the death of 50% of its consumers within a period of 50 days','Which when ingested once could result in the death of 50% of its consumers within a period of 96 hours','Which when ingested once could result in the death of 4% of its consumers within a period of 96 hours']
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of the following are included in the activities implemented for integrated environmental resource management?',
                answer: 'Awareness creation, creation of buffer zones, water abstraction licensing',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Awareness creation, creation of buffer zones, water abstraction licensing','Institution of environmental insurance policy, environmental laws, and law of conservation of matter','Creation of woodlots, community market creation, and creation of game reserve','Water abstraction licensing, application of inorganic fertilizers, and creation of game reserves']
            },
            {
                question: ' _______ tonnes of human waste are disposed untreated into water courses every day',
                answer: '2 million',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['2 million','200 million','5,000','2 billion','6 million']
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of the following is not identified with the Millennium Development Goals?',
                answer: 'Ensuring tertiary education for all',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Gender equality','Ensuring environmental sustainability','Ensuring tertiary education for all','Child and maternal health','Eradication of extreme poverty']
            },
            {
                question: 'Chloro fluoro carbons destroy the __________ ozone layer that acts as a screen protecting life on Earth from the sun’s harmful radiation.',
                answer: 'Stratosphere',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Mesosphere','Stratosphere','Thermosphere','Troposphere']
            },
            {
                question: 'In the Mazure relationship, __________ is used to determine the concentration of the contaminant in the water bodies.',
                answer: 'The dissolved oxygen content (COD)',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['The redox rate','The pH','The sulphates present','The dissolved oxygen content (COD)']
            },
            {
                question: 'A virus is normally described as a particle because it:',
                answer: 'Comprises one kind of nucleic acid covered by a protein coat',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Is easily mutable','Can be virulent','Comprises one kind of nucleic acid covered by a protein coat','Can develop into large populations outside the living host']
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of the following contribute to the precipitation of acid rain?',
                answer: 'H₂S, NO₂, and SO₂',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['NO₂, SO₂, and CO₂','HCl, NO₂, and CO₂','SO₂, NO₂, and SiO₂','H₂S, NO₂, and SO₂']
            },
            {
                question: 'In a microscopic analysis of a wastewater sample, a cover slip is used to cover a specimen deposited on a glass slide so as to:',
                answer: 'Prevent the specimen from drying up',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Prevent the specimen from being magnified beyond the range of magnification of the objective lens','Prevent crossing your eyes when viewing the magnified image','','Prevent the specimen from drying up']
            },
            {
                question: 'Taste and Odour of water samples are determined through the use of',
                answer: 'A panel of sensing experts and serial dilutions',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['A panel of sensing experts','A panel of sensing experts and serial dilutions','A panel of sensing experts and a comparator','A comparator with a remote sensor']
            },
            {
                question: 'Source constituents of alkalinity in natural water systems include',
                answer: 'CO₃²⁻, HCO₃⁻, OH⁻, HSiO₃',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['CO₃²⁻, HCO₃⁻, OH⁻, HSiO₃','CO₃²⁻, HCO₃⁻, OH⁻, CO₂','CO₃²⁻, HCO₃⁻, OH⁻, Fe(OH)₃','CO₃²⁻, HCO₃⁻, OH⁻, NO₃⁻, HSiO₃⁻']
            },
            {
                question: ' Water forms about ..........% of the human body mass',
                answer: '66',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['11','32','66','50']
            },
            {
                question: 'Using hard water in domestic activities poses a lot of challenges to laundry but could be useful to human health, especially children when consumed because:',
                answer: 'Hard water can contribute to the building of stronger bones and teeth structures',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Hard water can contribute to the building of stronger bones and teeth structures','Hard water can lead to the development of stronger IQ','Hard water can give rise to high concentration of enzymes in the organs','Hard has a pH above 7'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'In the development of an Environmental Impact Assessment report, development of a baseline information on the existing facilities and situation is necessary so as to',
                answer: 'Acquire knowledge of how the project will impact on the existing facilities, environment, communities, the flora and fauna',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Acquire knowledge of how the proposed project will be established','Acquire knowledge of how the project will impact on the existing facilities, environment, communities, the flora and fauna','Acquire knowledge on the skills to be employed for the proper development of the project','Acquire knowledge on similar projects and facilities in order to make successful and effective planning'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Preparation of the Environmental Impact Statement involves initial stages of scoping and screening',
                answer: 'True',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['True',' False',' Can not be determined','none of the above'] 
            },
            {
                question: ' What is the origin of apparent colour in natural surface and groundwater?',
                answer: 'Humus, iron and manganese ',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Humus, iron and manganese ','Iron and manganese','Humus and bauxite','Humus,industrial dyes and sullage'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'If two samples have the same turbidity values, then it means that the nature of the particles and their particle sizes are the same',
                answer: 'Can not be determined',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['True','Partly True','Can not be determined','false'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Without the sun, the earth’s atmospheric temperature would be about',
                answer: '67',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['250','67','38','15'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'The reflection of solar radiation back into the atmosphere is known as',
                answer: 'Albedo',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Emissivity','Albedo','Stratomos','Stratomos'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Which of the following is not a renewable resource',
                answer: 'Fossil fuel',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Fresh air','Fossil fuel','Fresh water','Solar energy'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Examples of indicator organisms include',
                answer: 'E. coli, and Enterobacter aerogenes',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Streptococci and Salmonella','E. coli, and Enterobacter aerogenes','Salmonella paratyphi and Enterococci','Streptococcus faecalis and Candida torulopsis'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Fresh water forms .....................% of the total water volume of the earth',
                answer: '2.7',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['2.7','10','5','30'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'Hard water do not form lather with soap because the soap will',
                answer: 'Precipitate as a calcium salt',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Precipitate as a calcium salt','Dissolve as sodium salt','Dissolve as potassium salt','Cause the garments to leach their dyes into the washing water'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'The atmospheric boundary layer of the earths atmosphere covers up to a height 5-2 km above the earth surface',
                answer: 'False',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['True','False','can not be determined','partly true'] 
            },
            {
                question: '..................... used primarily in fire extinguishing foam is capable of destroying ozone in the stratosphere.',
                answer: 'Chlorine',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Bromine','Chlorine','Halons','Furlongs'] 
            },
            {
                question: 'When determination of fecal coliform in water quality analysis is not conclusive, ......................... is used for confirmation',
                answer: 'Fecal streptococci',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Fecal enterococci','Fecal salmonella','Fecal candida','Fecal streptococci']
            },
            {
                question: 'To avoid global warming, the following must be done',
                answer: 'Afforestation, development of vehicles that run on electrical energy and solar energy harnessing',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Afforestation, avoid bush burning, burning of fossil fuels','Industrialization, cattle breeding, afforestation','Afforestation, development of vehicles that run on electrical energy and solar energy harnessing','Reduce population growth rate, practice appropriate animal husbandry, solar energy harnessing']
            },
            {
                question: 'Presence of algae in drinking water can give rise to',
                answer: 'Oxygen demand, color, formation of corrosive compounds',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Unpleasant taste, odor, turbidity, and toxic substances','Oxygen demand, color, formation of corrosive compounds','Color, odor, poor taste, and phosphates','Low pH, turbidity, and toxic substances']
            },
            {
                question: 'In analyzing a river water sample for the presence of fecal coliforms, using the multiple probable number (i.e. MPN) method, the seeded tubes are incubated for ........... hours at a temperature ...........°C.',
                answer: '18-24 hours, temp 37°C',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['18; 20','18; 45','36; 45','18-24 hours, temp 37°C']
            },
            {
                question: 'Hardness in water is attributed to the presence of elements such as',
                answer: 'Calcium, Magnesium, and other trace elements like iron and strontium',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Calcium, Manganese, and other trace elements like iron and strontium','Calcium, Magnesium, and other trace elements like iron and strontium','Carbon, Magnesium, Iron, and Manganese','None of the above']
            },
            {
                question: 'The two major types of Hardness in water are',
                answer: 'Temporal and permanent hardness',
                type: 'Multiple Choice',
                options: ['Temporal and permanent hardness','Moderate and real hardness','Metallic and non-metallic hardness','Carbonate and manganese hardness']
            },
        ]},
    }